Now that we have seen how to automate various task,
let us dive deep into debugging and exception handling in the UiPath.
In this lesson, we will learn about debugging in the UiPath.
We look at the debugging interface and the debugging panels in UiPath.
Next, we will learn about what are exceptions in
UiPath and how can we handle exceptions in UiPath studio.
Lastly, we will see how can we test
an individual workflows by passing a default value to it?
At the end of the lesson,
you should be able to understand and use debugging techniques to find errors.
Define exception handling, and use of different types of exceptions in finding error.
Run and test your automations with default values, and reusable code.