In this section, we will see how to perform testings on the activities that we have used.
For this example, we have chosen a form and we are
using the Type into Activities to input all the values inside this form.
Let us begin with the first option that is,
Run to this Activity.
The Run to this Activity is available when
right-clicking an activity in the Designer Panel.
In our case, we'll choose the company name and we'll right-click on the context menu,
and from here you can see the Run into this Activity.
Now, this option starts
the Debugging processes and pauses before the selected activity is executed,
while highlighting into the Designer Panel.
Let us run this and see it in action.
Click on, Run to this Activity.
Now you can see, the Bot is entering the values and as you saw,
the Bot has stopped the execution.
As you can see, we chose the Activity,
that is the Company,
and we chose, Run to this Activity.
So all the Activities,
that were before the Company Name,
was executed and the Debugging has been paused.
As you can see over here,
the First Name and the Last Name,
has been entered, and on the Company Name,
the execution has paused.
You can choose the option, Continue,
and proceed further or you can Stop your automation from here.
Let us see the other options that we have on the Designer Panel, Context Menu.
The second option that we have is,
Run from this Activity.
For this, we'll choose the activity role in the company.
Right-click on this, and here you have the option,
Run from this Activity.
The Run from this Activity,
context menu enters the debugging in a pause state,
which allows you to make changes to the values or
variables and arguments from the local panel.
Let us click on Run from this Activity.
Now, as you can see,
the Debugging is in a paused state.
Now the execution will start from the Role in the Company.
That means, all the activities which are above this,
Type into Activities, will be skipped and your execution,
will start from here.
You can even Edit the values from here.
For example, in our case,
let us change, the email address to something else.
Over here, the email address is, test10.
Let us change it to, test12.
Let us click on, Continue.
Here you can see, the Bot is entering the values into this field,
and you can see from here,
that the first three Activities,
did not execute and only the Role in the Company,
Address, E-mail, and the Phone Number, got executed.
As you can also see, the updated value is being displayed here.
You can also test an individual Activity.
For this purpose, we'll use the,
Type into Activity for the Phone Number.
Let us drag it out of the parent container.
When you do a right-click on this Activity in the Context Menu,
you see an option,
the Text Activity, click on the Test Activity.
The Text Activity, Context Menu option of the Designer Panel is
used for running a test on a current selected activities.
In our case, we are performing the activity on the Type into the Phone Number.
When you click, the local panel opens up,
which displays the variables and the arguments.
As you can see, we have the list of all the variables available,
but from here, we are only interested in the Phone Number.
We can do an Edit from this local panel,
and we can choose some random phone number that we want to enter.
Let us click on,
Continue, and now you can see,
only that particular activity was executed
and we have also changed the values from the local panel.
Let us look at the other option that is Creating a Test Bench.
The Test Bench option,
allows for creation of automation building blocks,
which can be tested and added to the final workflow.
In that case, we'll use the Type into Activity,
will do a right-click, and from here,
you can choose, Create Test Bench.
The Create Test Bench is similar to the Text Activity option,
with the exception that the later is contained and defined in an actual workflow.
It is used for testing activities,
working with variables or debugging the processes.
All this is done in a test bench or workflow,
that is a temporary sequence that is not
a part of the current project and it is discarded,
when we close it.
As you can see here,
our temporary sequence has been created
and this sequence is not available in our project panel.
When you close this temporary sequence,
it will not be Saved and the same will not be reflected in the project panel.
Let us go ahead and indicate a Notepad application,
where we need to type.
In our case, we'll type the message,
" Hello and welcome to test bench."
Let us Save, the workflow and let us click on, Debug.
As you can see, the Debugging is in the pause state.
As you can see, we have a two break points here.
The first break-point is where we have created
a Test Bench for the activities and we have another break-point,
that is ending this sequence.
Let us click on, Continue.
As you saw, the particular activity,
was able to perform the desired task.
That is, the Type into Activity was able to type into the Notepad and
now the process has again went into a pause state.
As you can see from here,
this is the only thing that is left.
Let us click on Continue and complete this Debugging process.
Awesome, that the Debugging process has been completed.
In this way, you can Create the Test Bench.
To summarize, the test activities,
we looked into Run to this Activity option.
We also looked at Run from this Activity, we also looked at,
how to individually test our activity in the workflow,
using the Test Activity option.
Lastly, we looked at how to Create a Test Bench for the activities,
that we're going to use, in the workflow.