With debugging and exception handling techniques that you have learned,
I hope this will help you to build
an automation that can handle exception while it is in production.
In this lesson, we learned about debugging in UiPath,
and saw the debugging interface and the panel in UiPath.
Next, we learned about exception handling and
the type of exceptions in UiPath and how to handle them.
We also looked at common exceptions in UiPath and the strategies to solve it.
Lastly, we looked at testing the workflows with a default value.
In the next lesson,
we will learn about the very important concept of UiPath, that is Orchestrator.