The process of identifying error or bug
in the running software or robot is called debugging.
It ensures that the error is identified and resolved so
that it does not impact the operation and the running of the robot.
It is a multi-step process that ensures that
the program to develop a software or application is perfect.
Debugging helps in maintaining the quality and
continuity of the code by resolving the errors.
It is the most important method by which developers identify the error or
[inaudible] in the developed code and make changes to get error-free program.
In the robotic process automation,
various tools have been provided by Uipath studio for debugging.
These tools are helpful to check the workflow of the programming structure,
and find the exception.
Apart from this, debugging also helps in checking
the execution process of each data point that is validated or checked.
On starting debug three panel appears on the workstation screen.
The local panel, the output panel,
and the property inspector panel.
Apart from these three panel,
we also have some more panels available which we will discuss after them.
The local panel, once we click on the brake,
a workflow that holds the data variable running in debugging mode appears on the screen.
The local panel will show the values of
all the variables and highlight the recently executing activity in yellow color,
which helps to find the data path.
However, all these things can happen
only when the data convention is assigned accurately.
The output panel is an essential panel in the RPA debugging.
It displays the detailed log of the current state of
the workflow and the status of all activities executed by the robot.
The properties inspector panel is used to show the active action properties.
Variable values, declaration, and debugging in the different data scope.
The immediate panel is only visible during debugging,
and it can be used for inspecting data available at a certain point during debugging.
It can evaluate variables, arguments, or statements.
To do so, simply type
the variable or argument name in the immediate window and press enter.
The immediate panel keeps the history of
previous evaluated statement and they can be
removed using the clear or context menu option.
To remove a single line from the panel,
select the text and press the space key.
When clicking inside a line and starting to type the text is added to the input field.
The call stack panel displays the next activity to be
executed and its parent container when the project is paused in debugging.
The panel, is displayed during execution in debug mode,
it gets populated after using step into break, slow step,
or after the execution was paused because an error or breakpoint was encountered.
Double-clicking an item in the call stack panel focuses
and highlights the selected activity in the designer panel.
If an activity throws an exception during debugging,
it is marked in the call stack panel and the activity is highlighted in red.
Similar to the call stack panel,
the watch panel is only visible during debugging.
It can be set to display the values of variables,
arguments, and user-defined expressions that are in scope.
These values are updated after each activity execution while debugging.
The breakpoint panel, displays all the breakpoints in
the current project together with the file in which they are [inaudible].
The activity name column shows the activity we did toggle the breakpoint.
While the file path column displays the file and its location.
The condition column displays condition set to break point.
The log message column shows messages to be logged if the condition is met,
hover over the breakpoint tag or an activity to view its condition and the log message.