In this example, we will see how to use the debugging tool from the UiPath Studio.
For that we have built a workflow which opens up
a Google form website and it reads all the values from an Excel sheet,
that is the challenge.xlsx,
and it inputs all the values into the Google form.
Now, let us try to debug the application.
For that under the ribbon bar,
navigate to the debug section and click on the "Debug Play Icon".
Now, you can see the debug process has
started and this is the web form that we are entering it.
Now, as you can see,
the debug process has stopped and as you can clearly see here in the output panel,
that we got an exception.
Now, the exception or the error,
it says that the input string is not in the correct format.
As you can easily notice here that this particular activity has been highlighted.
That means this activity is causing a trouble.
Now over here, the reason is very simple because we had a phone number text field,
and the conversion to the number did not happen correctly,
and so is the error that has been thrown to us.
Now, let us look at some of the options available in the debugging and being bad.
Over here, we have options;
Retry, Ignore, and Restart.
Now, as the name suggest,
Retry it will try executing this particular activity again.
Let us try executing this particular activity.
As you can see, it started and it said again that the activity was not able to perform.
Let us try again and as you can see here,
we've got the faulted message or the error here again.
Now we also have the Ignore and the Restart.
Now Ignore basically means it will skip
that particular activity and it will move forward.
As you can see here, this particular activity has been
ignored and we can say hit "Continue" to proceed further.
So as you can see here,
that the IT and the India was perfectly
executed and we skipped this particular phone number field.
We also have an option called as Restart.
Now, Restart basically will restart the whole debugging process again.
Now, before moving ahead,
as we saw that we had an header in
this activity that is the type into for the phone number.
Now, let us head back to the Excel workbook and see what exactly is causing this error.
As you can see clearly over here,
that the phone number is not in the correct format.
We have some alphabets also present in the phone number.
Let us edit the data and make it as a proper data.
Awesome. Now let us close the Excel workbook and let us
try executing or try restarting the debugging process again.
Now, before we start the debugging process again,
let us put a break point after the phone number field.
So we have a sequence here,
which is the phone number,
and we have a sequence that is for the department.
Now, adding a breakpoint over here means that
the execution will stop after the phone number field.
Let us restart the debugging process.
Now you can see easily the debugging process has been
started again and you can see John, Address,
and now you can see the phone number has been
correctly entered since we meet the edit in the Excel workbook.
Now the application is in the paused state because we have added a breakpoint here,
that means the workflow will not continue from this point.
Now, let us look at the other options that we have available here.
We have Step Into,
Step Over, and Step Out.
Now, as the name suggests,
step into the Step Into will debug all the activities one at a time.
Let us try using this Step Into option.
If I click Step Into for the first time,
as you can see, the Assign activity has been highlighted.
Now the Assign activity will be executed and you can see the logs for
that and it has taken the next activity that is the log message.
Let us click on this "Step Into" again.
Now you can see the log messages have been executed
and now the control is in the type into activity.
Let's click on the "Step Into" again and now you can
see the type into activity has been performed successfully.
Now let us see the option for the Step Over.
Now the Step Over is used when you want to run the entire container,
that is the sequence or the workflow together.
In this case, it will not execute each activity one at a time,
but it will execute the entire sequence,
that is the container in a single go.
Let us click on this "Step Over".
Now after that, we have that location.
Now let us execute this step over for the location.
The moment I click on "Step Over",
the entire sequence will be executed.
Now you can see it did not go into any of the particular activities,
but it executed the entire sequence,
that is Enter Location at one go.
Now, let us also look at the options,
that is the Step Out.
Now, as the name suggests, step out,
this action is used for stepping out and pausing
the execution or the level of the current container.
That means it will execute each and everything in
the parent container and it will pause
the debugging when it reaches the parent container again.
So in our case,
the parent container for us is this body activity,
which is inside the for each row activity.
Let us do a step out.
Now I can see the submit and submit another response was executed and it stopped
the execution when it reached
the parent container that is the body container in our case.
Now, let us look how to use the local panel in the debugging window.
Now here again, we have made changes into
the Excel file and we'll throw an exception when the debugging is running.
Let us start executing the debugging process.
Now you can see the debugging process has started and now at the phone number section,
we got the error again.
Now let us use the local panel and change
the values of the phone number and try continuing the debugging process.
Now in the local panel,
here you can see we have
all the variables available that we are using in the current sequence.
Now our variable, in that case is this phone number and you can easily see here,
the phone number has some alphabets present.
Let us click on this pencil icon and edit this data.
Awesome. Let us click on "Okay".
Now we can try the Retry option and let us see if it is executing perfectly fine or not.
Awesome. Now you can see that the phone number executed perfectly fine.
To continue with the rest debugging process,
we can click on this Continue icon and
the debugging process will execute in the correct manner.