An exception, is an activity or event that interrupts
the normal flow of the program when we run or execute a program.
An exception refers to the amount of deviation in the output,
shown from the required business or the agreed process.
In the software or bot programming exception handling is
responsive process that occurs during the execution or run-time.
Usually, developers do not want this to happen on program compilation time.
So to avoid this,
they check and pre-register an exception that can occur.
Some exceptions are handled fairly so that
the execution could start from where it was interrupted.
In short, exception handling is a precautionary method implemented to avoid deviations.
In UiPath there are two types of exceptions that are common,
business exception and system exceptions.
Let us talk about each of them in more detail.
Business exception.
The exception that occurs in a business process,
is called a business exception.
The exception is dependent on the type of business.
When an exception is caused due to the current working structure,
it is termed as a business exception.
For example, if you have to download an attachment from an e-mail,
then we need to have a unique identifier.
If the e-mail subject is not standard and keeps on changing,
the robot will not be able to pick the result in a business exception.
Any deviation from the standard business rule in any process or activity,
is called as a business exception.
Hence, to avoid the business exception,
we need to understand the business process very carefully.
To avoid business exception,
use a unique identifier.
In RPA, a business rule is defined as a set of
specific instructions on how the input and output of data should be processed.
System exceptions.
Every business process that we automate requires different application and tools,
such as Microsoft Office,
SAP, CRM, Oracle, and many more.
When the control flow of the automation process is
disrupted or stopped due to the failure of the system,
this is called system exception.
Example, it is mandatory to have Microsoft Outlook to automate a business process.
The robot picks the attachment from an e-mail and then downloads the same.
If the Outlook is not working,
the robot will not be able to open the attachment.
The error caused is due to
Microsoft Outlook failure and has nothing to do with the programming or business rule,
hence, this is categorized as system error.
A system error can be minimized by making the code error proof.
This is the remedial method used in UiPath studio to
identify the reason for failure and detect the error.
One of the most reliable method that we use in UiPath is a try catch activity.
In every automation process,
user wants to detect errors as they happen,
and perform various actions to rectify the errors when they occur.
Try catch activity is used to recover from a specific error,
instead of crashing and terminating the whole workflow.
The try catch activity can be found in the activities panel.
For handling errors in a try catch,
the user has to divide the whole workflow into three parts.
The first is the try block.
In this, the user has to put all the activities that might throw an error.
All the possible activities you create that causes error are placed inside this block.
The next is the catch block.
This is another very important activity to remove the error.
It is called catches in UiPath,
since the user can add multiple type of catches.
The last is the finally block,
it is the optional one.
It is just for the action to be performed after the try catch block.
In case of error or no error,
still, the final block will be executed.
Throw activity, it is used to throw
specific types of exception that a user want to throw,
and the catch can handle that particular type of exception,
and perform an action that the user wants to perform on that exception.
Rethrow activity throws an expression previously caught in an exception handling block.
We have already learned about the continue on error property in an earlier lesson.
Let us try to understand it in detail.
It is a property that specifies if the execution
should continue even when the activity throws an error.
Keep in mind that if the continue on error is set to true on
an activity that has a scope such as the attach window or the attach browser,
then all the errors that occur in other activities inside that scope are also ignored.
Having this property set to true is not recommended in all situations,
but there are some situations where it does make sense,
such as while using data scraping,
so the activity does not throw an error on the last page,
that is, when the selector of the Next button is no longer found.
The second situation is when we are not interested in capturing the error,
but simply in the execution of the activity.
This field only supports Boolean values,
that is true or false.
The default value is false, first,
if the field is blank and an error is thrown,
the execution of the project stops.
If the value is set to true,
the execution of the project continues regardless of any error.