In this example, we will try to read a data from an Excel file,
and we'll try to input that values into this web form.
Let us head back to the studio and let us see how can we
use or try catch activity to handle some exceptions.
Over here, we are using a Read Range activity and
this Read Range activity is reading the data from the "challenge.xlsx" workbook.
Let us open this workbook.
In this workbook, we have three records and for each and every record,
we have seven dates.
Now, since we are using the Read Range activity,
if the Excel workbook is open,
we will get an exception.
Let us run the workflow and see what is the exception that we get.
Here we've got the exception saying that the Excel workbook is already
being used by another process because of the Excel workbook is already opened up.
Now, let us try to handle such exception.
Moving ahead, first, we will encompass
the Read Range activity inside a Try Block activity.
To do so, right-click and choose the option,
Surround with a Try Catch block.
Now, in the Catches section,
we need to handle the Exception.
First, we will define an Exception over here.
We'll choose the Exception which is the most generic,
that is the System.Exception.
Here, we will add an activity.
Here, we will add a log message in the Catch log.
We'll choose the log level as Warning.
Over here, we will display what is
the exception message and what is the source of the exceptions.
For that, we need to save exception.Message and for printing the exception source,
you need to mention Exception.Source.
Now, let us try to handle the exception in the Catch log.
Since the Excel workbook is already opened up,
we'll use a Close Application activity.
Drag and drop the Close Application activity inside the Catch log.
Over here, we'll indicate the Excel file that we need to close.
Now, even if the Read Range activity
is not able to perform since the Excel file is opened,
the control goes to the Catch log.
In the Catch log, we first print the log message then we close the application.
Now, we can proceed further and we can read data from the same Excel workbook.
Before moving ahead over here,
we have read the data into a variable called as challengeDT.
Now in the Finally log,
we will read the data again.
Over here, we will specify a condition.
The condition is, "If the challengeDT is Nothing."
As in, if there is nothing read into the DataTable variable,
then we will use the Read Range activity again,
and we will read it over here.
Or else in the Else part,
we will do nothing.
For that, we'll just add a Comment activity,
and here we'll mention, "Do Nothing."
Awesome, let us click on "Okey."
Now, we have handled the mechanism.
Even if the workbook has opened or if the workbook is not open,
then also the workflow will run without causing exception.
Now, let us proceed further and see what we have.
Over here, we're using the ForEach row activity and we are
looping across each and every record from the DataTable.
Now, one of the record in the Excel file is mismatching.
As in, the e-mail address is not correct.
Let us open the Excel file and verify from here.
As you can see here,
the e-mail address of this field is not correct,
we will try to throw an exception when we encounter such situation.
Over here, we are using the Is Match activity.
In the Is Match activity,
we have configured it rejects for the e-mail address.
Over here, we're passing row of 5.ToString,
which represent the e-mail address column,
and we are checking that if it is valid.
Now, depending upon the Boolean output,
if the condition is valid,
as in, if the e-mail is valid,
then we will do the Type Into activity in the form.
Hence, we will throw an exception.
Over here since it is a Business Exception,
we will throw a Business Exception saying that the e-mail is not valid.
Then, the loop continues again for the next element.
Let us execute the workflow.
Our Excel file is still open.
As you can see, the bot successfully closed the Excel file,
now the value is being entered into the form.
The second value skipped,
and this is the third value that has been printed into
the form and the execution has stopped.
Out of the three records we have only entered
two records because one of the record field was faulty.
In the Output panel here,
you can see the exception.
That is, the Excel workbook exception.
Since we handled it,
the exception, the program brands successfully.
Here is the second exception that we explicitly through using the pro-activity,
which said the e-mail address is not valid.