In this example, we will do a division of two numbers and we'll
check if either of the numbers are divisible or not.
If not, we'll throw a business exception,
then while hiding the exception,
we'll check that if the first number is greater than the second number.
If not, then we'll re-throw the same atom.
Over here, we have used a try catch activity.
In the try block we have used another try catch activity.
Over here in the try activity,
we are checking if the first number mod second number is equal to 0.
We have created two variables of number 1 and number 2 of the type integer.
Initially we have assigned the value 48 and 24.
Now if the division mod is equal to 0,
then we'll just print a message saying it is divisible.
If demand is not equal to 0,
then we'll throw a business exception and in the business exception,
we'll say that the numbers are not divisible.
Since now we are throwing the exception,
the control will go to the catch block.
Let us go and see what is there in the catch block.
Here, in the catch block,
we are printing out the exception and then we are again
checking that if the first number is greater than the second number.
If yes, then we'll say applicable or else we will re-throw an error.
Now this re-throw will go to the catch activity of the parent try block.
Over here we are just printing the exception that is;
the number is not divisible.
Let us run this workflow.
Initially we are using 48 and 24,
that means the mod is equal to 0.
Let us check the output.
Over here, it says divisible which is perfectly fine.
Now, let us go ahead and change the value from the variables panel.
Now, let us give a value which is greater than 24,
but which is not mod of 0.
For example, we will take the value as 25.
Save the workflow.
Now let us run the workflow.
Let us open the output panel,
and over here you can see we've got the exception.
This exception is from re-throw activity.
Now, after the activity has thrown an error,
the control went to the catch block.
In the catch block, we are checking if the number 1 is greater than number 2.
Since the number 1 was greater than the number 2,
record the message as applicable.
Now, let us do the last modification.
That is, let us consider a number which is smaller than the number 2.
In our example, we'll put the number as 20.
Now, let us run the workflow.
Now, let us open the outward panel and see the output.
Over here, since the mode is not equal to 0,
the throw activity throws an error and this is the error that we got.
Now since the number 1 is also smaller than
the number 2 the re-throw activity is also throwing the same error.
In this way, you can use the re-throw activity to throw the same error.