To start out for the exercise solution,
we have created three variables here: name and age and we have a DataTable variable,
the name is PersonInfoDT.
Now, depending upon the user input,
that is the user enters a correct age format,
we will build a DataTable.
In DataTable, we have the name and the age field,
and we will write the user input into the DataTable.
Later, we will also write the data into CSV file.
If the data enters a wrong format for the age,
then we will throw a exception.
In the catch block here,
we have chosen a message box and we'll print
the message to the user saying that you entered an invalid data.
Let us run this workflow.
Let us enter a name and let us give the age.
For this first run, we will give the age in a correct format.
Awesome, the workflow has completed.
Now over here, let us do a quick refresh
and let us open the.CSV file that has been created.
Here you can see that the data that you entered
has been successfully entered into the CSV file.
Let us close this and let us run the workflow again.
Now, let us provide the name and in this case,
let us provide data which is not in the number format.
Let us give some random text.
Now let us click on "OK".
Here we got the exception saying that," Your data that you entered is invalid."