Let us look at the solution for this exercise.
The bot will read this Excel file and it will
calculate the difference between the selling price and the cost price.
As you can see here,
the data is not correct for all the fields that we have.
We have some alphabet for some of the cost price and the selling price.
Now the bot needs to do the subtraction,
that is the selling price minus the cost price.
If the data in the cost price and in the selling price are in the correct number format,
the bot will do the difference and put the values
here and it will set the status to success.
If the data is incorrect,
say for example in this case,
we have 13K and we have 130.
This is an incorrect data.
In that case, the bot will not perform the difference but
it will set the status to incorrect data in the cell.
Let us see a solution for it.
Here in the UiPath Studio,
under the sequence we have started with
a "Read Range" activity which reads the Excel file,
and we're storing it in a variable called as "CashDT."
Now we have used a "ForEachRow" activity to
look through all the records in the Excel file,
that is the data table.
Here we have used a "TryCatch" block.
In the try block, we are using these two assign activity where we are
fetching the values of the cost price and we're fetching the values of the selling price,
and we're converting them into a string using the CINT method.
Next, we are performing the difference,
that is the selling price minus
the cost price and we're writing it into the corresponding cell.
To write into the corresponding cell,
we are using a variable called as "cellNumber."
Now in the variables panel,
the "cellNumber" default value is 2 because the
first is the header and we have to start from the second row,
and each and every time we are incrementing
the cell number by one so that we can increase the row value.
Next we're using another "Write Cell" activity.
This is to write a message "Success" and in the catch block over here,
we are specifying that if the number conversion format is not proper,
then over here first we use a "Log Message" to throw
the exception that is the number conversion could not
happen and we're using a "Write Cell" activity.
In the "Write Cell" activity in the status column will
set the status as incorrect data in the cell.
Let us see the workflow in action.
Let us save the workflow and let us run the workflow.
Awesome. The bot was able to complete the process.
Now let us do a quick refresh and open the Excel file.
Here you can see all the differences has been
added and for the values which was incorrect,
the difference could not be calculated and
the status is set to incorrect data in the cell.