Welcome to the second lesson of this course.
Here, we will mainly focus on how to extract information from the screen.
In this lesson, we will learn recordings in the UI part
and we will also see what are the different types of recording in the UI part.
Next, we will look at these scraping techniques.
Here, we will learn about the screen scraping mechanism and
the data scraping mechanism and also look at the advanced scraping mechanism.
We will look at the image and text automation in the UI part and we will look
at the Citrix automation and what are
the challenges that we face in the Citrix automation?
At the end of this lesson,
you will be able to differentiate between actions that can be
recorded automatically and actions that have to be manually recorded in UiPath,
use the basic desktop and web recording
and know the situations in which each of them is appropriate,
use the screen scraping wizard and configured
input and output methods as appropriate to the context,
use the data scraping functionalities of UiPath in the appropriate context,
learn how to perform basic image and text automation,
as well as virtual machine applications automation.