Data Scraping is the process of extracting structured data from a browser,
application or document to a database,
that is a CSV file or an Excel spreadsheet.
It is used to create a data table at runtime.
It can extract all the pattern-based data
and store it into the form of a data table automatically.
Data Scraping always generates a container that is attach browser or attach window,
with a selector for the top level window and an extracted structured data activity.
This activity will extract data from the indicated webpage using a partial selector,
ensuring the correct identification of the app being scraped.
All the script information is stored in
a data table variable that can later be used to populate a database,
that is a CSV file or an Excel spreadsheet.