In this data scraping example,
we will scrape the title of the book and the date from the Amazon.com website.
To begin that, we have already used the open browser activity.
Within the open browser activity,
we have mentioned the amazon.com URL.
After that, we are using a type into
activity and then we are searching for the automation books.
Now, we will start our data scraping tool.
To do that from the ribbon bar,
click on data scraping.
A new window comes up.
Let us try to understand what does is window asking?
The window has three steps in it.
The first step is asking you to open up your browser or
the application or the document from where you want to scrape the data.
In our case, the Amazon page is already opened up.
The next step it says,
press next in this dialogue box and then hover over
the data that you want to extract and then click that field.
We'll click the Next button and we will hold upon the data that we want to extract.
In our case, we want to extract the book title.
We'll click here. A new window comes up,
but just asking us to select the second element.
This is because we want to create a pattern.
Click on Next and click on the Next Book Title.
Here, you can give a name to the column as you are
extracting more than one information that is more than one book title,
you will be storing it in the form of what column.
Now here, we need to give a column name.
Let us give the column name as book title.
Awesome. We have an additional option here,
which is extract the URL.
Now, this works upon the data which has a URL embedded behind it.
In our case, when we click on any of the book title,
it takes us to a new web page.
Basically there is a URL embedded behind it.
The data scraping tool can also extract the URL from it.
We will click on this and we will name this column as URL.
Click Next. Here you can see we have
extracted all the book title and the URL from the first page.
Let us verify the last data.
The last data is the condensed Handbook of Measurement and Control,
and we have the last book there.
Now let us try to understand what are the fields in this window?
The first field that we are interested is the maximum result field.
Over here, by default,
it is set as 100.
That means the data scraping tool will scrape 100 data.
If you want to scrape all the data,
you have to mention zero.
Else if you want to explicitly mentioned any custom number,
you can give the number here.
In our case, we will extract 50 records.
The next button is the extract co-related button.
Now this button is responsible to extract more data from the same page.
In our case, we want to extract even the date.
To do that, we'll click on extract correlated data,
and we will point towards the date.
I click on that.
Now, we also have to make a pattern for the date.
Click on Next and point out to other date.
Awesome. Now you can see all the dates have been taken by the data scraping tool.
Give a name to this column,
we'll give the name as date.
As you can see the extract you had an option is still available,
but in our case there is no URL behind the date and neither there interested in it.
We will make it as uncheck and we will proceed further.
Awesome. Here you can see we have now the book title and the URL,
and we have the next column that is date.
If in case you want to scrape more data,
you can click on extract correlated data and scrape more data accordingly.
Now, we'll click on Finish.
Here there is another window which pops up,
and it is asking, is your data spanning in multiple pages?
That means is your data here spanning in multiple pages?
If yes, then click on yes and point
to the button from where you can navigate to the next screen.
In our case, the button is here.
Awesome. Here you can see we have
the data scraping tool and inside the data scraping we have the extract data.
Here we will just add a delay between multiple pages.
We'll add a two second of delay.
By default, all the data that has been scraped will be stored in a data table.
The data table name by default is kept as extract data table.
If you want you can change the variable name.
Now, the next thing that we need to do is we need
to store this data table into an Excel sheet.
We will use a right range activity,
drag-and-drop derived range activity.
Within this right range activity,
we will pass the workbook URL.
In our case, we will create the workbook.
We will name the workbook as automation books with the extension.
Over here, you need to specify the data table that you want to write.
In our case, the data table name is extract data table.
Awesome. Make sure you click on the add
headers so that your column names is also included.
Let us run the automation.
As you can see Amazon page is opened up,
automation book was search and now the multiple spanning of the pages will begin.
Now, the automation has completed successfully.
Let us verify the Excel file.
Let us open this excel file and here you can see we have the book title,
we have URL and the date.
We have 51 record because the first entry is the column name.