In this exercise, we will use the Data Scraping UiPath
and we will scrape the blocks from the white part page.
To do so, let us use the data scraping tool.
Here, we will scrape the block from this particular page,
and here, we will scrape only the RPA blocks.
Click Next and indicate the RPA block.
Let us create a pattern.
Let us scrape one more RPA block.
Awesome. Let us give a column a name.
We'll name it as RPA block and click on Next.
Here, you can see the RPA blocks that have been scraped.
Here, we are only interested in 15 blocks,
and we'll click on Finish.
Now, here, it is asking,
is the data spanning in multiple pages?
Over here, the Load More button will act as spanning in multiple pages.
We'll click Yes, and we'll indicate on this button, Load More.
Awesome. Now, we'll drag and drop the right range activity after the data scraping.
Over here, we will save the data into an Excel sheet with the name block.
As you can see, there is no block created.
Now, let us run this automation.
Over here, you can see the UiPath block page has been
opened up and the data has been successfully scraped.
Let us do a refresh, and over here,
you can see the Excel file has been created.
Here are the 15 blocks that we have scraped.