Relative scraping is one of the advanced scraping techniques.
It is based on OCR engine,
but it uses it for recognizing the character and
choosing another UI element as an anchor for the forced UI element.
This results in the following order of activities.
First, the process will attempt to identify the anchor, and second,
it will search for the UI element to scrape data from
using the relative positions on the screen.
This is particularly useful while selectors are unavailable for various reason.
UI elements are not recognized directly or
the activities apply to all virtual environments, such as Citrix.
The attribute of a UI element,
such as exact screen position or its ancestor can be extracted.
Data scraping is about getting texts from UI element using various methods.
In certain circumstances, this is not the easiest thing to do.
UI path offers several activities that may come in handy,
such as Get Ancestor.
As you may recall from the selector lesson,
UI elements are in parent-child structures.
This is always visible from the structure of selectors.
First general classes, then particular classes,
then sub-classes, and so on.
When you open up a notepad file,
the selector will go up to the notepad app,
then to the category of app that Notepad is a part of, and so on.
Get Ancestor retrieves the ancestor or the parent of a UI element.
Get Attributes.
UI element have plenty of attributes.
Think of a button on a website.
It has a color or name or state, and so on.
Get Attribute is the activity that enables the identification of a certain attributes.
The user can specify the attributes and
the activity retrieves the value of that specific attribute.
Get Position.
This activity retrieves the actual position on the screen of a specific element.
It can be very useful when there are many similar elements on the screen.
Without knowing the actual position,
it would become very difficult to identify them.