In this example, we will see how to use the image recording.
Image-based automation relies on the user interface element recognition.
It is helpful in the situations where UI automation fails to work.
This basically happens when the selector cannot be found using the regular method.
In our example, we will use the Citrix environment.
In this Citrix environment,
we will automate this application.
[inaudible] will open up this application,
and we will fill some values into the application.
To begin, we'll pick on the Recording and we'll choose the image recording from here.
Now, we'll use the Click Image and we will mark a boundary across this application.
We can set the mouse position to center,
top-left, top-right, or the bottom left, or the bottom right.
Or else, you can also specify a point where you want to click,
that is the center of the icon.
Awesome. Now, let us try to input some values into this text field.
We'll make use of the text activity,
and we'll enter the first value.
We'll make use of the text-based automation,
or the keyboard shortcuts available,
and we'll try to enter the rest of the values from here.
To do that, we will use the tab hotkey and we'll enter the next value here.
We again use the tab value,
and we will enter the next value from here.
Awesome, let us click "Enter."
As you can see, all the three values were entered using the keyboard shortcuts,
let us save and exit.
Here you can see all the activities have been made available here,
such as the Click and the Type Into activity.
Let us go ahead and run this automation.
As you can see, the bot has started and it
has entered the values into this corresponding field.