UiPath version 2018.4.1 onwards,
has native support for Citrix Virtual Apps,
formerly known as the Zen App.
By installing the Citrix Extension on the client machine and
the UiPath Remote Runtime component on the Citrix Virtual App application server,
we can automate Citrix App as if they were local applications.
Selectors are natively generated for Citrix App element,
and we can use the full range of UiAutomation Activities,
such as Click, Type Into,
Get Text, Extract Text, and more.
However, this is not the case with the Citrix Virtual Desktop called as Xendesktop.
UiExplorer is unable to extract selectors
for element inside the applications in a Citrix Desktop application.
The same is the case with Citrix Virtual Apps,
where Citrix extensions are not enabled.
In this scenarios, we have to rely on image,
text, and keyboard automation.
When and where to perform these certain actions.
The concepts of automation can be fully utilized in
cases where the errors in the automating projects are minimal.
For example, when waiting for a particular state of an application,
it is essential to create optimal automation,
that waits for the application or a web page to load,
or for a specific process to end.
At this point, we look and wait for the visual element to appear,
by keeping the On Image Appear on it.
A better and more gentle solution is
to wait for the application loading icon to disappear.
An On Image Vanish activities can be used for this purpose,
allowing the automation to continue,
or leave when the loading icon vanishes.
Certain activities accept control to be already present in the normal field.
Sending data to the application,
or extracting data from the application,
are some of the such scenarios,
where we can get data by using click activities,
like Click Image and Click Text.
Apart from these, you can also click on an anchor image relative to the text.
You can also achieve this by using keyboard activities,
like sending tab keys.
Identifying the elements.
Virtual environment do not provide any way to identify UIElements through standard means.
Therefore, visual anchors are the only options.
You can use the image or the extracted text,
to compare with the expected result.
UiPath Studio features activities that uses
OCR or image recognition technologies, in such situations.
Several OCR engines can be used with the UiPatch Studios,
like Google Tesseract, Microsoft MODI, and ABBYY.
Google Tesseract engine works better for scraping smaller areas,
while Microsoft MODI is more suitable for the larger ones.