In this example, we will see how to use the Native Citrix Recording.
But before starting, let us try to understand more about the Native Citrix recording.
The Native Citrix recording option allows you to identify
the UI element in the Citrix app and automated them.
Whereas on the other hand,
the image recording that we have already used still exists
to perform the traditional image and the text-based automation.
By installing the UI path extension for Citrix on the
client machine and the UI path remote runtime component
on the virtual application server,
you can now create automation projects for Citrix app as if they were local applications.
Selectors are natively generated for Citrix app element,
and you can use the full range of UI automation activities,
such as click, typing to get text,
extract data and many more.
In that case, over here,
we have a Citrix environment.
In this Citrix environment,
we will try to type the information into the notepad and we'll try to save it.
To begin that from the recording,
we will use the Native Citrix.
Over here, we'll start typing into the Notepad.
As you can see, the selector is been readily available.
We'll type the message as Citrix recording.
Awesome. Hit enter.
Now we'll click on the file.
There is no need for anchoring it.
Now, we will click on Save As.
Awesome. Now, we will use a type into activity to give a name to the file.
We'll save the file with the name Citrix.
Lastly, we'll click on the Save button.
Now, we will close this application.
Let us save and exit the recording.
Here you can see the activities available for them.
Let us run the application.
Before that, we'll open up the notepad application here.
Now, let us run the automation.
Perfect. We were able to run the automation successfully.