Firstly, we will learn about recording.
That is, we learn about the basic recording,
the next stop recording,
and the web recording in UiPath.
Next, we will learn about the types of UI interaction.
Here, we will speak about the input and the output action.
Next, we will learn about the scraping techniques in UiPath.
Here we will learn about the screen scraping,
we will learn about data scraping,
and we'll also see what are the advanced scraping techniques.
Next, we will learn about how can we use an image and a text automation.
Lastly, we will learn how to automate a Citrix environment,
and we will see what are the challenges in the Citrix environment.