Recording is an important tool in UiPath Studio.
It captures our limits every activity step by step.
The UiPath recorder works in the same way as Macros Recording app.
It automatically generates the sequence of
all the activities which we need in the workflow for automation.
Apart from this, it also allows you to modify
the property of activities and change it in the workflow sequence.
How does it work?
Let's start with an example which you are already acquainted with.
That is the Excel Macros.
In Visual Basics Application or the VBA code,
we use Macros to record steps.
These steps can be things like typing,
clicking on cell or command on a ribbon bar or a menu bar,
formatting cell in a spreadsheet or importing data from an external source,
such as Microsoft Access.
This way, the user saves time on
predictable and repetitive tasks without having to write a single line of code.
The recorder in the UiPath is a particular activity capable of
working with different types of apps or different types of environment,
identify the element on the screen,
reading data from the screen, and so on.
The list of actions that the UiPath recorder can automate is as follows, left-click,
check boxes, drop-down list that is showing them,
and also choosing the element and typing the text.
Apart from this, the recorder does not automatically record some activities,
such as keyboard shortcuts like Control C,
Control V, modifier keys,
that is the Shift and the Control mouse,
right-click and mouse hover.
UiPath has many types of recorders,
and here are a few that you will commonly encounter.
That is, Basic, Desktop,
Web, Image and the Native Citrix.
The three that we will cover here are the Basic recording,
the Desktop recording, and the Web recording.
The concept of Image and Native Citrix will be covered later in this lesson.
The recording wizard for all the three types of recorders
consists of three types of component, Save & Exit.
This option is enabled only when the recorder is on.
It closes the recorder and reverts to the designer window,
display the automatically generated activities.
The next is Record.
It starts automatic recording mode in which multiple input activities are generated.
The user will see a blue screen over the area where
an action is captured and yellow outlines for selectors.
The last is a Manual Recording Actions.
Here, the options are Starting Apps,
Clicking, Type into, and so on,
actions that the user can select to
generate single activities during the recording process.