Let's first understand the difference between the type
of recorders to understand better each recording mode,
and the environment they operate.
The basic recorder: a basic recorder is used to automate the desktop application.
It is used when we only want to work with a single window.
Desktop recorder: a desktop recorder records the desktop application,
when multiple actions are performed in numerous windows.
While recording, it fixes all operations inside the attach a window container.
Web recorder: it is used to automate activities
performed on website using one of the three major browsers,
that is IE, Chrome, and Firefox.
It is used when we want to act on any web-based applications and website.
All the actions that we perform come under the attached browser activity.
Image recorder: it uses images for all virtualized environment.
The automation cannot identify all the application.
It relies on image recognition.
First the position of the element used in automation is needed.
Citrix recorder: native Citrix is used for
Citrix environment that were configured to support new iPad native Citrix.
The configuration involves installing several apps and plugins on the client
and server machine and using studio 2018.4 or later.
Once the setup is made,
native Citrix generates selectors and works like the desktop recorder.
Let us understand the difference between a basic recorder and the desktop recorder.
Basic recorder is used with multiple windows when it causes the interference problem.
It generates default selector.
For example, if you have to write something in Notepad,
you open an untitled Notepad and perform your actions inside it.
The basic recorder does not use the container.
Your iPad uses the name of the currently open file name of
the application title of the window to identify the correct window on the screen.
In some cases, multiple windows are identical.
Suppose it opens two untitled windows at the same time
then your iPad will perform all actions inside the first open window.
Because in this case,
the title of both Notepad application is same, that is untitled.
The next is the desktop recorder.
It is used when multiple actions are performed in many windows.
It nests all activities inside the attach a window container.
It uses container to ensure that other activities
of the same application don't interfere with your workflow.
The top-level window selectors are inside the attach window and it
generates the partial selectors for activities inside the attachment window container.
Automatic recording is used for recording multiple actions in one time.
There are four activities that are automatically generated using automatic recording.
They are, click, type into,
select items, and check.