In this example, we will learn how to use the recordings in UiPath.
First, we will start with basic recording and then move to desktop recording and lastly,
we will see how to use the web recording.
For the basic recording from the ribbon bar,
click on ''Recording'' and click on the ''Basic recording.''
This is the Window which comes up for the basic recording.
Here we will use the Notepad application for building the automation.
We will type into the Notepad and we'll save the Notepad.
To begin with, first,
we need to open up the Notepad.
For that, we'll click on the ''Start Apps''
and we'll select the ''Start app activity from here.''
Will point to the notepad and it is asking us,
"Is this the application that you need to open up?"
We will say confirm,
we need to open this notepad.
You can skip the argument for now.
Now we will use the automatic recording and we will continue further.
Next is, we need to type.
We will point to the text area over here
and we will type the message in this balloon box.
The message that we will type is UiPath.
Here we have two options.
Type password for typing password and empty field.
The empty field options allows you to erase
the pre-existing text and then write the new text.
Once the text is written, press ''Enter.''
Here you can see the bot has performed the type into activity.
Next, we'll click on ''File.''
Hold your mouse to the file and then perform a click.
Now it's asking you,
"Do you want to use an anchor?"
We have learned about anchors in these selectors chapters.
In our case, there is no need to anchorate because the file location or
the file is always going to be in the same place for each and every notepad application.
We will ignore this.
We will say, ''No, we do not want to anchorate.''
Next, we will click on ''Save as.''
Perfect. In this new Window,
we have to give a file name.
We will hover the mouse over the file name text box and we will click here.
Now this activities are so smart that they
can differentiate between the click and the type.
Now this is a type activity hence,
we got the balloon to type your name.
Here we will type the file name.
We'll type the file name as UiPath and we'll make sure that we check the empty field.
Press ''Enter.''
Next is we need to save the Notepad.
To do that, we'll hover over the save button and we'll perform a click.
To stop the recording,
you have to press the Escape key from your keyboard.
Here you can see in the desktop the file has been created.
Next, we can click on ''Save and exit'' to get out of the recording.
Here you can see all the set of activities that we have performed is available.
Starting from opening of the notepad,
typing into the notepad,
performing the file, and then save as,
then lastly clicking on ''Save.''
Let us run this bot.
The bot was able to perform the desired task.
Now, let us move ahead and see the next recording.
That is the desktop recording.
For desktop recording also we will do
the same exercise that is automating the notepad application.
On the ribbon bar,
click on ''Recording'' and click on ''Desktop.''
This is the Window that comes up for the desktop recording.
To start with, we will say start up and
will indicate the notepad application. Click on ''Okay.''
Here we will again use the automatic recording option.
We will point out to the text area where we want to print or type our data and
we will type the text as the Udacity and hit ''Enter.''
Next we'll click on ''File.''
There is no need for anchoring it.
We'll click on ''Save as'' and here we will give a name.
We'll say with the name Udacity, hit ''Enter.''
Next, click on the ''Save button'' and escape the recording.
Here you can see the Udacity file has been created.
Click on ''Save and exit.''
Here is all the activities that we have used in the recording.
Now, the bot will perform the same task as in it will open up the notepad,
type Udacity and save the application.
But now let us see the difference between
the basic recording and the desktop recording as we have learned earlier in the lessons,
that the basic recording gives us
a full selector and a desktop recording gives us a partial selector.
Basically, what we want to do is the basic recording does not use a container,
whereas a desktop recording always uses a container.
Here you can see all the activities are grouped into one sequence.
We can look at the selector for the same.
Over here, when you look at the selector,
each and every selector includes the parent node.
Here, we can also see the same thing.
Let us look at the desktop recording.
Here in the desktop recording,
you can easily see that you have a container for the different set of activities.
This is one container.
Here is the second container,
and here is the third container.
This helps us to generate a partial selector.
Here, you can look at the selector for the type into activity.
As you can see here,
this part has been grayed out.
That means it comes from the parent activity,
as in it comes from the open notepad application.
All the activities inside this container will follow the parent node.
Let us look at the third type of recording that is the web recording.
Here we'll navigate to the IMDb movie rating website.
We will search for a movie and we will display the movie rating to the user.
To begin so click on the ''Recording'' and click on the ''Web recording.''
Here is the Window that comes up for the web recording.
Over here, the first thing that we need to do is,
we need to open up the browser.
Click on the ''Open browser'' and say open browser.
Point anywhere on your webpage.
Here is the URL and we'll confirm,
yes, we need to open up this web page.
Next, we can start with the automatic recording.
Click on the ''Recorder'' and over here we will input the movie name.
I'll input the movie name as Joker and hit ''Enter.''
Next is, we need to click on this particular movie,
that is the Joker movie.
Awesome. The next thing that we need to do is,
we need to get the ratings from here.
To do that, we will escape from the automatic recording and from the manual recording,
we will select the ''Copy text.''
We will point out to the rating area over here.
Awesome. Let us save and exit the recording.
As you can see, all the activities have been displayed here,
right from opening up the browser,
typing the movie name,
clicking on the movie,
and here we have a Get Text activity which fetches the rating from the webpage.
By default, there is a variable created called a span.
You can verify it in the variable panel.
We will change the variable and we will name
the variable as Rating to make it much more meaningful.
Now, we need to use a Message Box activity and inside the Message Box activity,
we will display the rating to the user.
Drag and drop the Message Box activity after the Get Text and give the input as rating.
Perfect. Now let us run this automation.
Now you can see the web page has been opened up.
The movie name was searched and the movie was clicked.
Now, here the Get Text activity is working and here we are displaying the movie rating.