Screen scraping is the process of extracting
data from a specified UI element or a document,
such as a PDF file.
Screen scraping methods are the core of all the activities
that enables data from a specified UI element or document.
In some cases, data is sent directly to
the user or from one activity to another by using variables or arguments.
But in other cases,
other methods are needed to take data from various screens or document.
This is the screen scraping methods are used.
They enable data extraction from UI element that the automation workflows interacts with.
Screen scraping wizard enables the user to point
at a UI element and extract text from it.
The steps are, starting the screen scraping wizard from the design ribbon in the UiPart.
The screen goes into a computer vision mode,
highlighting the UI element that it defines with blue.
Once the user selects the UI element,
studio automatically chooses a screen scraping method.
After it finishes extracting the text,
the wizard shows the outcome.
The user can select one of the three methods and customize it using the properties.
Clicking the refresh button displays the outcome according to the new settings.
FullText output method.
The FullText output method is the default output method in UiPart.
It is the fast,
accurate, and can work in the background.
It captures all the texts from the terminal screen,
including the hidden text.
For example, the options in the drop down list.
It does not work on Citrix and different virtual environment.
It does not retain formatting and text position as well.
The method offers the following options, ignored hidden.
When ignored hidden method is selected,
it offers the option to ignore the hidden messages and capture only the visible text.
The native output method.
It can be used only with the applications that are
built to render with a graphic device interface.
It is useful when the coordinates of each word,
font, and color of the text are required to be written accurately.
However, it has its limitations as well.
It only extracts the visible text,
cannot work in the background and does not support Citrix.
The method offered the following options.
No formatting, when the font and color are not necessary to be captured,
this box can be checked and the wizard extracts or leave
the text just like the FullText method, get words info.
This option can extract the position of each word and can support several separators.
By default, it can process all known characters as separators like comma, or space.
But when specific separators are specified,
it ignores the other.
Additionally, the custom separator field is displayed enabling
the user to determine the character used as a separator.
If the field is empty,
all known text separators are used.