OCR output method, although both full text and
native have excellent result in terms of accuracy and speed,
there are specific cases in which both are unstable.
For example, if we need to extract information from
a virtual environment or read text from the images,
the optical character recognition output method should be used,
it is based on the OCR technology used in the recognition of scanned documents,
it attempts to recognize each letter or given an image in the target document.
It is slow compared to the other method, has lower accuracy,
it varies from one text to another,
it cannot extract hidden text,
and it cannot work in the background.
The OCR methods has two default engines,
Google Tesseract and Microsoft MODI.
The use of this engine depends on the type of information being extracted.
In general, it is better to switch between the methods to see which
of the engine brings better results for each particular situation.
If the user has downloaded and installed the package of other OCR engines such as AMI,
they will also be available by choosing the OCR engine.
Google Tesseract OCR, this method gets better results for
character recognition on the smaller size area and it supports color inversion,
it offers multiple customization through filters that
can be used to select only a specific categories of character.
This method offers the following options: Language,
this is English by default, Character,
enables the user to select which type of character to be extracted.
The following options are: any character, numbers only, letters,
uppercase, lowercase, phone number,
currency, date, and custom.
When custom is selected,
two additional fields, allowed and denied,
are displayed that enables the user to create custom rules
of which types of characters to scrape and which to avoid.
The next is Invert,
when this check box is selected,
the color of the UI element are inverted before scraping,
this is helpful when the background is darker than the text color.
The next is Scale,
the scaling factor of the selected UI element or image,
the higher the number,
the larger the image,
this can provide a better OCR read and it is recommended for small images.
Get Words Info, it gets the on-screen position of each scraped word.
Microsoft OCR, this method is used to work with Microsoft fonts and on larger size area,
it supports multiple languages.
This method offers the following options: Language,
enables the user to change the language of the script text,
by default, English is selected.
Scale, the scaling factor of the selected UI element or image,
the higher the numbers,
the larger the image,
this can provide a better OCR read and is recommended for small images.
Get Words Info, it gets the on-screen position of each scraped word.