In this example, we will look at the various screen scraping methods.
Firstly, we will scrape the data from this notepad.
In this notepad, we have some data which is not visible to the human eye.
Now, let us try to do a screen scraping on this notepad application.
To begin that, click on the "Screen Scraping" option on the [inaudible] back,
and point out to the text area from where you want to screen the text.
Over here, you can see by default the scraping method is taken as full text.
Over here, you can also verify that
the full text was also able to scrape the hidden data,
that is this part of the data.
Now, let us change the method to a native and click on "Refresh".
As you can see, the native methods was only
responsible to scrape the data which is visible in the screen,
that is till this part that is growth.
We can also choose the third option,
that is the OCR option.
In the OCR option,
you have two OCR engine available,
the Microsoft OCR and the Tesseract OCR.
Let us go ahead with Microsoft OCR and click on "Refresh".
The OCR is comparatively slow than the full text and the native methods.
Even the OCR also captures only the part that is visible on the screen.
Now, since this is our text application,
the full-text was able to retrieve all the information,
that is the hidden information also and the native and the OCR,
were only able to retrieve those part which is visible on the screen.
Now, let us use an image.
This is an image and we will try to apply all the three scraping methods in this image.
To begin with, we'll click on the "UI Element",
and we'll indicate the area that we want to screen.
Awesome. Here you saw the full-text method field to scrape the region.
Let us try again with the native.
Click on "Refresh".
The native method also has failed doing it.
Now, let us click on "OCR".
We'll go with the Microsoft OCR first.
Click on "Refresh".
Awesome. Now you can see the Microsoft OCR was
able to extract all the information from this text available.
Since this is an image,
it's not a text format,
the other two methods that is native and full text,
were not able to extract or scrape the data.
In this case, OCR is the only help that is available.
Now, we have two options for the OCR,
the Microsoft and the Tesseract.
Let us go ahead and choose the other option that is the Tesseract and click on "Refresh".
The scaling factor, we will set it at as 1.
OCR will take compatibly more time than the other two method.
Now, you can easily see the OCR was able to
extract the text from it but if you see very carefully,
the text are not extracted in the correct manner.
For example, if you see this text over here,
there is a space in-between here but here,
as you can see, there is no space added.
Tesseract OCR only works with the small size of the images,
whereas Microsoft OCR works with the bigger size of the images.
Changing it to Microsoft OCR and keeping the scale as one that is the same,
we'll click on "Refresh".
Now you can easily see Microsoft was able to scrape the data accurately,
as you can confirm from here.
We can also make the Tesseract OCR to do the same thing by increasing the scale factor.
If you increase the scale factor,
the scraping time is comparatively more.
Let us wait for the data to be scraped.
Now you can see the data has been scraped accurately.
Depending upon your application,
you need to test which OCR engine works
best and what is the scaling factor that is going to help you.
Apart from the scaling factor,
we also have options for characters and choosing the languages.
The Microsoft OCR has only choosing the language and the scaling factor.