Welcome back and awesome work on completing the first two lesson,
and starting with the third lesson.
The world is full of data,
so is the RPA world.
We need to alter the data as per the process need,
to make it more meaningful and readable to both human and the robot.
In this lesson, we will learn about string manipulation,
collection, its type, and how to perform manipulation on collection.
We will look at some common UI properties,
and we will also look at the overview of.NET Framework and VB.
At the end of this lesson,
you will be able to;
describe data manipulation and its importance,
apply data manipulation methods suitable for RPA to
different types of data structures and variables, explain collection,
its type and manipulation,
understand and correctly use the properties of
UI interface activity to make them robust, reusable, and scalable.