Now that we have learned about dictionaries,
let us look at an example to see how to use dictionaries in the UiPath studio.
Moving ahead, first, we'll create a variable of the type dictionary.
Under the variable panel,
we'll create a variable with the name employee details.
We'll choose the variable type as dictionaries.
Since dictionary is not available here,
we'll click on "Browse for Type" and from here we will filter out dictionaries.
Select the dictionaries from the class collection.generic.
For the key value we will select the key as
string and for the value we'll select "List of String".
We will search for list and we'll choose
the list from the collection.generic class and
over here we'll select the list value as string.
Awesome. Now, the dictionary key is string
and the value as list of string. Click on "Okay".
Now, we have declared a dictionary of the type key as string and value as list of string.
Now let us go ahead and instantiate the dictionaries.
Over here we'll see new dictionary,
and since we have key and value so we'll see off string because key is off string,
and since the value as a list,
we'll see list of string.
Awesome. Now, we have declared the string and we have instantiated the string.
Now, let us go ahead and initialize the dictionaries with some values.
For that, we'll use the assign activity.
Drag and drop the Assign activity into the data in the panel.
Now, let us go ahead and create our dictionary key.
In that case, we'll create a key with the name HR.
Now, let us go ahead and initialize it with some values.
Here, we'll say new list of string,
and let us insert some values.
The first value that will insert is David,
and we will insert other value.
The second value here would be Daniel.
Awesome. Let us click on "Okay".
Now, we have created a dictionary where the key is
HR and the value with the key is David and Daniel.
Let us go ahead and create another dictionary.
In this case, we'll name the key as IT and in this IT department,
we will add values.
In our case, we'll name the first employee in
the IT section as Niyaz and the another employee as Heba.
Now, we have created two dictionaries.
The first dictionary key HR and it holds the value David and Daniel.
We have an another dictionary where the key is IT and the value here is Niyaz and Heba.
Now, let us go ahead and print one of the dictionaries.
We will use our write line activity.
Now in this write line activity we'll call the joint method so we'll say string.join.
Here, we'll use comma to join both the values and here we will have to pass the key.
The key in our case that we want to print is IT.
Awesome. Let us go ahead and click on "Okay".
Let us run the workflow.
In that case we are trying to print values of the key IT.
As you can see, the value we have printed is Niyaz and Heba.
Now, let us go ahead and add more values into to the dictionaries that we have created.
We can use the collection activity,
drag and drop the Add to collection.
Now, in this Add to collection in the collection properties,
we need to mention in which dictionary do we want to add values.
In that case, we will mention
that we need to add it into the employee details of IT.
Let us change the type argument to string.
Now here is where you need to add the values.
In that case, we will add the value as Christa.
Now, let us go ahead and print the dictionary.
We have used two write line activities and we are printing the employees of IT.
In this write line we are assuming there should be two values,
Niyaz and Heba, and we added one more value, that is Christa.
Here, we are assuming that three values should be printed.
Let us run the workflow and see the output.
Awesome. Here, you can see Christa has been added and it has been accordingly printed.
In the same way, you can also check if any of the element exists in the collection,
drag and drop the existing collection.
Here in the collection section,
we will mention the employee of HR,
change the argument type to string.
Here, we will see if David exist in this dictionary or not.
Since the result will give us add Boolean value,
let us go ahead and create a variable.
We'll name the variable as employee exist.
If the employee David exist it will return a true value,
or if it does not exist it will return a false value.
Let us go ahead and print the Boolean variable.
We'll use a write line activity again and over here,
we'll print the variable employee exist and we'll convert it to string.
Let us run the workflow.
In there under the output panel,
here you can see the value has been printed as true that
means David was available in the dictionary that we were searching for.
The same way you can also use the Remove from collection.
Drag and drop the remove from collection and over here we
need to mention the collection or the dictionary.
In our example, we will tell we need to remove a value from the HR dictionary,
convert the type to string,
and from here we will remove David.
Awesome. Now, let us use the write line
again and print the value after the removal of the values.
Let us change the department to HR.
Let us save it,
and let us run the workflow.
Awesome. Here you can see we've got
the Niyaz and Heba and then we added Christa so Christa was printed.
Then we were searching if David is available.
Yes, David was available and David existed in the dictionary as we got true.
Since we removed David from the dictionary and then we are printing the dictionary,
here you can see there is only Daniel available right now.
In this example, we saw how to create,
declare and instantiate a dictionary,
and how to add a value into the dictionaries,
and we saw how to use the collection activities with the dictionaries.