Now, we have learned about the common UI activities properties.
Let us try to implement it in this exercise.
Here, we will work on the notepad application.
First thing first, we need to open the notepad application.
After opening the notepad application,
we need to type our text into the text box.
This is the text that we need to write into the text box
that is," Automation makes life easier."
After that, you need to minimize the notepad,
making sure that when the board minimizes the notepad,
the simulate click property is checked.
Next, we need to type a different set of text.
We will be typing,
"Welcome to the new world of automation".
When the boat is typing this text,
we'll have to make sure that the send window message property is checked.
Later, we need to change the font type,
default style, and increase the font size by five.
To do that, we'll select the entire text,
click on "Format", click on "Font",
change the font type to Times New Roman,
and change the font style to Italic.
Now, you can see the font size is 28.
We need to increase the font size by five.
Now the current font size should be 33.
We need to hit the "Enter Key". That's it.
Let us build the application for this use case.
Before going ahead, let me change the format.
Let me just increase the font size a little bit.
Here is the solution for the application that we just saw.
As you can see, we have started with the "Sequence",
and we are using the "Open Application".
In the "Open Application",
we have make sure that we are opening up the notepad application.
Inside the open application,
the first thing that we're doing is,
we're using the type into activity.
In this type into activity,
we will write," Automation makes life easier."
After that, we'll click on "Minimize".
As you can see in the properties panel,
the "SimulateClick" has been checked to "True".
After that, we will type the different set of information that is we'll type,
"Welcome to the new world of automation."
On the properties panel,
you can see the "SendWindowMessages" option,
is checked as "True".
After that, we are using "Send Hotkey" activity,
wherein we are choosing "Control plus K", as the shortcut.
We are doing so, so that we can select all the text and then we can edit the font,
the font size, and default style.
After we have selected all the text,
we will click on the "Format" button.
After the format button,
we'll click on the "Font".
Now, once you are in the font window,
we will use the "Type into" activity.
This first "Type into" activity,
we are using it for changing the font type.
The next "Type Into" activity,
we are using to change the font style.
We will change the font style to Italic.
The next activity is the "Get Text" activity.
Here, we are first checking what is the default font size available.
The Get Text will take the value of the font size,
and will store it in a variable font size.
Now later, we will use a Type Into activity,
and the value that we fetched we'll increase it by five.
On the last, we will send an Hotkey,
that is the "Enter Key",
to close the format window.
Let us run the boat.
Minimize. As you can see,
"Welcome to the new world" has been already written.
Changing the font style and the font size.
Here you can see,
all the actions were performed successfully.