Now that we have learned some of the common methods of VB,
let us use them in this exercise.
In this exercise, we will move some files from a particular folder to another folder.
Here you can see in the next step,
I have two folders named from and to.
The from folders has four files into it.
It has a document file,
a PDF file, a text file, and an Excel file.
We will move all these files to the folder "to".
Let us see the solution for it.
Inside the sequence, the first activity that we are using is the Select Folder activity.
In this Select Folder activity,
we will be selecting the source folder.
After that, we have used an assign activity.
In this assign activity,
we are using directory.dotgetfiles method.
From this method, we will take all the files or basically,
we will fetch all the files from the source folder and store it in a variable file name.
After that, we are again using a select folder.
This activity is responsible to select
the destination of the folder where the files will be moved.
We're using a variable destination folder for it.
Inside the 'for each' activity,
we are iterating or each one of the file name one at a time.
Inside the file loop,
we are using an activity move file.
The move file activity has two parameters,
the from and the to.
In the from we're parsing the file name,
and in the to destination,
we are parsing the destination folder.
Let us see the example.
Right now, all the files are in the 'from' folder.
Here you can see it is asking me to select the source folder.
I'll select "from".
Again, it is prompting to select the destination folder, I'll select "to".
The bot has successfully executed.
As you can see here,
the "from" folder is empty and all the files have been moved to the 'to' folder.