We'll start with data manipulation and we will introduce what is data manipulation.
We will speak about the difference between data query and data manipulation,
and we will look at some of the basic data manipulation operators.
The next is the string manipulation.
Here we will introduce string and look for the methods for manipulating strings,
and we'll look at the regular expression.
The next topic is the collection.
We'll introduce collection and the types of the collection,
and we'll look at how to use collection manipulations.
The next topic is the UI activities property.
Here we will look at some of the common UI properties.
The last topic we'll do an overview of the.NET Framework and VB.