Data manipulation is the process of changing data to
make it easier to read or to be more organized.
Manipulating data can enable it to be displayed in a common format of systems,
output verifications and beyond.
Common operations for data manipulations are, retrieving data,
it specifies a condition to extract,
filter or summarize data.
Adding data, it adds new data in a data structure.
The user can specify conditions to limit the additions only to the filtered entries.
Deleting data, it removes entries from a data structure.
Modifying data, any type of operations
that affects the existing entries in a data structure.
Data is defined as a collection of information that can be stored and processed.
Nowadays, data is the topmost priority for organization.
Whoever has data has the most power to use technology at their best.
Organizations are in deep competition to
utilize and maximize their efficiency by having data.
Having raw data is not enough,
it needs to be processed accordingly before it can be used.
However, having data is not enough as it should mean something to the company.
Meaningless data could prove to be unreliable and impossible to analyze.
Data manipulation covers all the operations done on data.
Operation done on data can be differentiated based on how they achieve an outcome.
There are two types of operation, queries,
they may only be considered as read Only operations because whenever a query is executed,
it only works at a static source and returns the value accordingly.
Manipulations, these operations produce alteration over the data structures.
These operations may be inserting,
deleting, or modifying data.
Data manipulation is used for data filtering, verification and concatenation.
Most of the data manipulation language share four basic commands,
select, update, insert, and delete.
This command do not cover all the data processing techniques,
but by using conditions and configurations,
complex manipulations can be performed.
Let's see a basic outline of these commands.
The Select command, this is used to extract,
filter, and summarize data.
The second command is Update,
this is used to add a new columns.
For example, fields, remove or update the existing one.
The third is Insert,
this is used to add new data,
for example, adding new rules.
The last is the Delete,
this is used to delete the entries by using a condition.