String is the data type corresponding to the text that contains any sequence of text.
Almost every automation scenarios involves string as they are used anytime.
A form of text needs to be captured,
processed, sent between applications, or displayed.
Let us now look at some of the operations that can be performed on strings.
The first method is concat,
concatenates the string representation of two specified object.
Contains, checks whether a specified substring occurs within a string.
It returns a Boolean value that is true or false.
Format, converts an entire expression into a string.
It reduces complexity and increases readability.
IndexOf, returns the zero-based index
of the first occurrence of the character in a string.
Join, it concatenates the element in a collection and displays them as string.
Replace, identifies a sequence of character of
the string type in a text and replaces it with a given string.
Split, it splits a string into substring based on a criteria set by the user.
This delimiter could be space,
comma, or any specified character.
Substring, it extracts a substring from a string using the starting index and the length.
It is used to isolate or separate a substring from the original string.
Trim, this removes all occurrence of
a character from the beginning and the end of a string.
Basically, it removes all the white spaces from the starting and the ending of a string.
ToUpper, it converts all the character in a string to uppercase.
ToLower, it converts all the character in a string to lowercase.
ToString, it returns this instance of a string.
No actual conversion is performed.
For further string manipulation methods,
there will be a link provided in the classroom for reference.
Regular expression or commonly known as RegEx is
a specific search pattern that can be used to easily match,
locate, and manage text.
UiPath studio contains a RegEx builder
that simplifies the creation of a regular expression.
Using the RegEx search capabilities in selectors enables
the user to identify multiple target elements with a single search execution.
Without RegEx, multiple selectors would have been built to identify each target element.
RegEx can be used in string validation,
string parsing, data scraping, string manipulation.
For example, RegEx can be used for retrieving a piece of a text that
follows a certain pattern such as
extracting phone number that starts with a certain digit.
The RegEx builder is integrated as three activities applicable in UiPath.
They are Matches.
It searches and inputs string for all occurrences
and returns all the successful matches for the given expression.
It can be used to retrieve all the entries and use them further.
The second activity is the IsMatch.
It indicates whether the specified regular expression finds a match in
the specified input string and returns only a true or a false value.
It can be used as a condition for another activity.
The last activity is Replace,
it replaces string that matches
a regular expression pattern with a specified replacement string.
It can be used for data quality purposes.