Let us try to retrieve some information from the string using Analytics Builder.
To do that, under the activities panel,
we will use the activity name, matches.
Drag and drop the activity into the designer panel.
Click on the Configure Regular Expression button.
This window, is the regex builder.
Before proceeding further, let us copy some test data into it,
so that we can test our regex over here.
This extra information, it contains some numbers.
It contains an e-mail address,
it contains website URL,
it contains the date of birth,
and it also contains some address.
Let us go ahead and look at
all the options that are available under the regex drop-down call box.
The first one is the literal.
As you can see, the default value is given as abc,
and since there is no text present,
abc, so there was no string retrieval happen.
Let us go ahead and change it to a data that we have in the text.
As you can see, the value has been changed to niyaz,
and all the values from the string or the text has been retrieved.
Let us look at the other options, digit.
Here you can see all the numbers from the string has been retrieved.
We can look at the options such as e-mail.
Here, you can easily see
the e-mail addresses has been successfully retrieved from the string.
We can click on URL and you can see the URL
has been retrieved from the entire string text.
The date, from the entire text available,
the date was easily retrieved.
Let's click on phone number.
Here you can see the phone number has been
successfully retrieved from the entire piece of information.
Apart from that, you can also add your own custom regex that you need.
In our case, we need to find the office address.
To do that, we will click on the Advanced option,
and inside the value,
we will pass the regex.
Now you could see easily the addresses has been retrieved successfully.
If you look at the regex,
we are looking for numbers ranging from 1-8 and characters ranging from a-z.
Apart from that, we are looking for some of the keywords such as;
road, avenue, circle, and so on.
With the help of this regex,
we are able to get a variable to retrieve the address successfully.
Let us go ahead and build a program.
In this sequence, we will retrieve all the numbers from the string,
and we will display it into the output panel.
To do that, we will take an Input Dialog activity,
drag and drop the Input Dialog activity,
let me give a title to this dialog box.
Here we'll enter the label for the Input Dialogue box.
We will store the text entered by the user into a variable.
Hit "Control K" to create a variable,
and let me give a variable name.
The variable name is a regexText.
That means the information that the user is
entering will be stored into a variable called as regexText.
Now, I'll use the matches activity.
I'll click on the "Configure",
since I want to only use digits,
I'll click on the "Digits",
and I'll click on "Save".
In the properties panel,
I'll pass the input variable.
Our variable is regexText.
On our regexText variable,
the digit pattern will be applied and we will get a new set of result.
Let us store it into a new variable,
hit "Control K" to create a new variable and let us go ahead and create a new variable.
New variable created is digit.
Since it is going to have more than one value,
we'll have to use a loop.
We'll use a For Each loop over here to iterate through all the values.
Drag and drop the For Each loop.
Pass the regex outcome over here, that is digits.
For every iteration we will print the item.
I'm using the right line activity here for printing the values in the console,
and I'll be using items.
Let us execute this program.
Here there is the Input Dialog box,
which is asking a text from the user.
We'll use the same text that we saw earlier.
Click "Okay". The program has been successfully completed.
Let us open the output panel,
and here you can see all the digits from the text
has been retrieved successfully and we have printed it.