In this exercise, we will use string manipulation methods and apply it on a string.
We have the string available with us.
The string is, you always wanted to study automation training.
The materials are available in the following places: Udacity, UiPath Docs.
From the first sentence,
we need to extract study Automation Training.
From the second sentence,
we need to extract Udacity and UiPath Docs separately.
Lastly, we need to combine them and print this message that is,
study Automation Training from: Udacity; UiPath Docs.
Let us see the solution for it.
Inside the sequence activity,
we have used an assign activity.
In this assign activity,
we have assigned the predefined text where manipulation will happen.
We are storing it in a variable called as, "message."
In the next assign activity,
we will start splitting the text.
Via first splitting the text with respect to a delimiter that is, period.
That means, from this entire string,
we will split the string with on basis of this period.
Now, we will use a substring method and in that substring method,
we will substring it with the keyword, "study."
That means from the first split that happen,
we got this information.
From this information, we will use
a substring method and we will split it on the keyboard study.
That is, we have this piece of information available.
Now, this will be stored into a variable called as, "study."
Next, we are again using an assign activity.
In this assign activity,
we will further split the string,
we'll use the message variable and in
that message variable will again split it with respect to the delimiter,
that is, "period. "
So we will split again with respect to this period over here.
Now, we're interested in this text.
Now from this text,
you can see easily we have given the area number one,
because when you split the string,
the result is stored it in a form of an added.
So, in the zero position,
we have this information,
and in the first position we have this information,
as we are interested in this piece of information,
so we have explicitly mentioned the area position
here will convert it into a string and again,
we will split it with respect to, "colon."
That is, we are going to split it with respect to this delimiter.
Now, we are interested in this piece.
That is the reason we have used, Last.ToString.
Again, we are splitting it with respect to,
"comma" because we need Udacity and UiPath Docs separately,
so now, this is the delimiter that we're going to use.
Now, we will store this information into a variable, "study."
Sorry, we will store it into a variable, "places."
Lastly, we are using the message box activity to print our final message.
In the message box activity we are using the format method.
In the format method we have passed two arguments.
The first argument, is replaced by "study" variable,
and the second argument,
is replaced by places medium.
But before using the "places" variable,
we are joining it with respect to, "semicolon."
Let us run the board.
Here you can see the output patterns,
study Automation Training from: Udacity; UiPath Docs.