Now that we have learned the common string manipulation methods,
let us use it in the exercise.
Here, we will build a workflow that converts an integer to string.
To do so, you'll ask a set of inputs from the user.
You will ask the name of the user,
and you will also ask the age of the user.
Depending upon the age provided,
we need to calculate the year birth of the user.
Let us see the solution for it.
Here inside the sequence,
we're using Input Dialog activity.
In this Input Dialog activity,
we are asking the name.
The input is stored in a variable, username.
In the second Input Dialog box,
we are asking it from the user.
The input will be stored into a variable called last userAge.
As you can see in the Variable panels,
we have userName of the type string,
and we have userAge of the type integer.
The next activity is the Assign activity.
In this activity, we will calculate the user year of birth.
To do so, we will do a simple calculation that is the present year minus the userAge.
To find out what is the present year,
we will use the Now.Year property.
For Now.Year will give you the current year.
So it's Now.Year minus the user age,
and we will assign it to a variable yearOfBirth.
As you can see, in the Variable panel,
the yearOfBirth is an integer variable.
Now, we need to convert this integer variable into strings.
In the Message Box panel,
we have the custom message and the message is, "Hello, username.
You were born in the yearOfBirth".
We'll use a ToString method to convert it into a string.
Let us run the bot.
Here you can see it is asking for a username.
There you go, the age,
we'll say the age is 28.
Perfect, you got the output.
"Hello Heba. You were born in 1992".
The year in which the video was recorded is 2020.
Hence, we got the date of birth as 1992.