A collection is used to represent a set of similar data type items in a single unit,
which is used for grouping and managing the objects.
It is useful in cases when the user wants to extract
the data in the Excel spreadsheet and the orchestrator queues.
We will learn about the orchestrator queues in the coming courses.
The different types of collections are;
arrays, strings, lists, and dictionaries.
We have discussed arrays and strings previously.
We will be discussing lists and dictionaries here.
Lists are data structures consisting of objects of the same data type,
for example, string or integer.
Each object has a fixed position in the list,
because it can be accessed by an index value.
While arrays are fixed sized structures for storing multiple objects,
lists allows the user to add,
insert and remove items.
Lists are one of the simplest and most used collection data types.
Lists can store large numbers of elements,
such as names, numbers, time coordinates etc.
Lists provides a specific methods of manipulation,
such as adding and removing items,
searching for an item,
looping through the item,
and then performing certain actions on them,
sorting the object and extracting items and converting them to other data type.
A dictionary is a collection of words and their meanings.
Dictionaries consists of keys and values pair,
in which the keys are unique.
Here, key is equivalent to word and value is equivalent to a meaning.
Example, address book in mobile phone,
where each name has corresponding data,
that is, the phone numbers and email.
The data type for both key and value have to be chosen when the variable is instantiated.
Datatype in dictionaries can be of the supported variables.
The operation that are most often associated with dictionaries are;
adding and deleting that has key value pair,
retrieving the values associated with the key,
and reassigning a new value to an existing key.
Uipath studio offers the following methods for manipulating collections;
The Foster's add to collection,
it adds an item to a specified collection,
it is equivalent to a list dot add method.
Example, it can be used to add a new name to a list of company name.
Remove from collection; it removes an item from a specified collection and
can output of Boolean variable that confirms the factors of the removal operation.
For example, it can be used to remove
an invoice number from a list of invoices to be processed.
The third is, exist.
It indicates whether a given item is present in
a given collection by outputting a Boolean as a result.
Example, it can be used to check whether a list of client contains a specific name.
The last is, clear collection;
it clears a specified collection of all items.
For example, it can be used to empty a collection
before starting a new phase of a process that will populate it again.