Now that we have learned about list,
let us look at an example where we can see how
to implement or how to use list in the UiPath Studio.
To begin that, first we'll open up the variable panel,
and inside the variable panel will create a list variable.
The variable name in our case is employee name.
We'll choose the variable type as list.
As you can see, list is not available here in the drop-down box,
we'll click on "Browse for Type" and here we'll search for list.
Make sure you choose the list from the System.Collection package.
We'll choose the type of the list as string,
and we'll click "OK".
Here we have declared our list and now let us go ahead and instantiate the list.
Here, we'll specify new list of and we'll pass string.
Now we have declared and instantiated the list,
let us go ahead and add values inside the list.
To do that, we'll make use of the collection activities.
We'll use the Add To Collection activities.
In the Add To Collection activities here,
we need to specify the collection name.
We'll go here and specify the collection name that is the employee name,
that is the list basically,
and here we will type the value that we want to insert into the list.
Let us change the type to string.
Perfect. We'll use the same Add To Collection
and we will insert two more values in the list.
We'll change the name to Niyaz and here we'll add the third value into the list,
and we'll name this as David.
Now let us use a For Each activity and in this For Each activity,
we will print all the values inside the list.
Here we'll pass the list name,
that is employee name,
and here inside the For Each activity,
we will use a Write Line activity.
Now here we'll specify item.ToString.
Let us run the automation.
Let us check the output panel and here you can see
the three values that we added into the list has been displayed.
Now let us go ahead and use the other activities from the collections.
Now, let us go ahead and use the Exists in Collection.
The Exists in Collection basically tells if the element is present in the list or not.
Here we specify the list name, the list name,
in our case is employee name,
and we'll check if David is present in the list.
Let us change the argument type to string and since
the Exists in Collection will give us a value saying yes,
the element exist or the element does not exist,
that means the return type is Boolean,
as it can also confirm from here that the output is in the form of a Boolean.
Let us go ahead and create a new variable for storing the result.
Control K for creating a new variable,
and we'll have the variable name as employee exists.
Now, let us go ahead and do Write Line activity
and let us print the variable name, that is employeeexists.ToString.
Let us run the workflow.
Let us check the output panel,
and here you see we got the value as true because David is present in our list.
Perfect. Let us use the other activity.
Let us make use of Remove From Collection.
In this example, we will remove David from our list.
First, we need to specify the list name,
that is employee name,
and here we will specify that we need to remove David from the list.
Change the argument type to string.
Let us run the workflow and check if David is actually removed from this list or not.
Let us open the output panel and here you can see David has been removed.
But here you can see we still got the true value because
the exist was called before removing from the list.
Let us use the last activity present that is Clear Collection.
The Clear Collection basically removes all the elements from the list.
Let us use the same for each loop again,
and we'll print the values and let us see if we are
able to print any values after removing elements from the collection.
Now here we got true because David was present here.
Now since we remove David and then we printed all the elements,
we got Heba and Niyaz.
Now later we have cleared the collection and after clearing the collection,
we are using the For Each activity again.
Now since the collection is empty,
we're not able to print any values from the list.