Namespace are containers which hold groups of unique names.
Let's understand namespace through an example.
College A should not have two students with the same ID and neither College B should.
But there is no problem for the same ID number to be used in both these schools.
If Heba is a student in College A and Daniel is a student in College B,
then it is not a problem for each of them to have the ID 123.
In this example, the ID number is the identifier and the college serves as the namespace.
It does not cause problem for the same identifier
to identify a different student in each namespace.
VB.NET namespace in UIpath Studio represents
the container that store different types of data.
They enable you to easily define the scope of your expression, variables, and arguments.
Some namespace are automatically imported when you
browse for a dot-net type variable or argument.
For example, if you have System.Data namespace imported,
you can further use data table,
data view, data column,
data row, and other classes that are available in it without
having to always type the system.datatable and so on.
All imported namespace are displayed in the import panel.
Note that some namespace are automatically
imported when you browse for a dot-net type variable argument.
To open this, click Imports in the designer panel.