In your iPad, control flow,
is enacted using two separate concepts that influenced each other.
The type of the project,
that is workflow, and the control flow statements that can be used.
Let's take them one by one.
Here we will learn about the three types of workflows in new iPad.
They are sequence, flowchart, and state machines.
In your iPad studio,
a sequence is a container in which multiple activities
are placed one after another and executed linearly.
Within the sequence, an activity is followed by the next activity in a linear fashion.
The sequence can contain any number of activities,
but no activity can be skipped during the execution.
The program, when run must execute each activity linearly with
no possibility of skipping an activity or branching off to another activity.
A sequence can either solve as a standalone automation project or can be included
as a part of a workflow or a state machine to help grow the specific activities.
One of the key features of sequence is that it can be reused time and again.
In this section, we will learn about workflows
in your iPad and how are they different from sequences.
A flowchart is a type of project that consists
of various activities which can be connected to one another in multiple ways.
It is diagrammatically approach,
which represents various steps involved in completing activities, task, and processes.
This helps the user to easily view and follow the process.
Flowchart can either be used as
a standalone automation project or included in procedures of large projects.
The most important aspect of flowchart is that unlike sequence,
they represent multiple branching logical operators that
helps to create complex business processes and connect activities in multiple ways.
They're two activities used to decide the flow of a program inside flowchart.
These are flow decision.
It is an activity which executes one of
two branches depending on whether a specified condition is met.
The branches are titled true or false by default,
but the names can be changed in the Properties panel.
This activity can only be used in flowchart,
and if equivalent to the If activity.
Important properties of these activities are condition,
true label and the false label.
The condition is used to analyze before one of the two branch is executed.
This field supports only Boolean expression, true Label,
enables the user to provide a description of the case in which the condition is met.
The description can be removed by
holding the mouse cursor over the flow decision activity.
By default, this is filled in with true or false label,
enables the user to provide a description of the case in which the condition is not met.
The description can be viewed by holding the mouse cursor or the flow decision activity,
by default, this is filled in with false.
Here you can see we have a flawed decision here,
and you can see the two labels here are true Label and the false label.
If the flow decision control evaluates to true,
it goes to the true label.
If the flow decision control evaluated to be false,
it follows defaults label,
and then it executes the corresponding activities.
The second one, the flow switch.
It is an activity that splits the control flow into
three or more branches out of which
a single one is executed based on a specific condition.
This activity can be used in a flowchart and as equivalent to the switching activity.
Here you can see we have flow switch,
it has multiple branches and each branch serves as a different case.
There is a default case available if none of the cases get much,
the sequences of the default is selected.