Loops are structures used to automate the repetitive task.
A certain section in the flowchart may be required to perform
repetitive task and hence loop can be used inside the flow chart.
In flowchart, the simplest type of loop can be created by connecting a certain point in
the workflow to an earlier execution and
repeating the task until the specified condition is met.
Here you can see we have a flow decision in the diagram.
When the control evaluates to true,
a set of sequences is executed.
After the effect of sequence is executed,
we are looping back again to the input dialog box.
Nesting is vital while creating complex workflows as it
allows a logical division of the program and promote reusability.
Although it is technically possible to nest workflows and sequence in every way,
the only sustainable combination is to use a flowchart to represent
the overall logic of the program and to use sequences for different parts.
In sequence the process step flow in a clear succession.
Activities in sequence are easier to read and maintain.
Decision tree are rarely used in sequences.
They are highly recommended for simple and linear workflows.
In flowchart, steps are represented through a diagram.
The individual activities are a bit more difficult to read and edit,
but the flow between them are much clearer.
Use flowchart when decision points and branching are
needed in order to accommodate complex scenarios,
walk-around and decision mechanism.
State machine is a container for using state machines specific activities.
It contains a start node that can be linked to the initial state of this state machines.
A state is a container where we can put our activities.
There are two types of states in UI path;
state and the final state.
A state machine is divided into following blocks.
Entry. It allows a path to start the activity by the entry process.
Exit. It allows a direction to end activity by the exit process.
Transition area.
It describes the current transition this state has about the other states.
Note, final state has only one block.
For example, entry.