Now that we have learned about the types of workflows in UiPath,
let us implement it in this exercise.
Here we will use a flowchart and
a sequence and we will print a custom message using them.
To begin so, we'll open the main.xaml file.
Under the activity panel,
we will search for a sequence activity.
Drag and drop the sequence activity in the Design panel.
In the sequence, we will use or write line activity for
the custom message making sure that
the custom message always has to be within the double quotes.
Here the messages is,
"Professor is the mastermind of the heist."
Now, we will use a flowchart activity inside this sequence activity.
Under the Search bar in the Activities panel search for Flowchart.
Drag and drop the flowchart here.
Click on to open the Flowchart activity.
Inside this Flowchart activity,
we will use a Write Line activity.
In this Write Line activity,
we will print another custom message.
Here the message is,
"Berlin is the second-in-command of the Professor and he is his brother."
We will connect this activity to the Start Node.
Perfect. Let's get back to the main.xaml file.
Now here we have a sequence and in this sequence we are
printing a custom message using Write Line and after this we are using a flowchart.
Inside this Flowchart, we are again printing our custom message.
Let us execute this program.
The execution has completed successfully.
Let us open the Output panel and see our output.
Here you can see we got the message,
"Professor is the mastermind of the heist."
That is the sequence and,
"Berlin is the Professor's second-in-command and brother."
Which is coming from the Flowchart activity.