Control flow is the order in which activities or
actions are executed or performed in a workflow.
Control flow, if enacted through control flow activities which are
used to define the decision to be made during the execution of a workflow.
The execution of control flow activities help
the user to choose a suitable path to follow in the workflow.
These activities are found in
the activities panel under the workflows activities section.
The flow of an automation projects can be controlled in two ways.
The first one is the decision based control.
Here, a decision is made on the basis of a specified condition.
If the condition is met,
the program executes one part and if not,
then it executes some other part.
This consist of the if and default activity.
The second type is the iteration based control flow.
Here, a particular part of a program is executed many
times until a specific condition is met or it holds through.
This consists of loops such as while,
do while, and for each.
In addition to these two types,
there are other types in your iPod that helps the user to control the flow of execution.
This includes activities like dealey, parallel, assign, etc.
These activities are discussed in details in the coming section.