Deficient based control helps the user to decide
the execution flow of a program based on certain conditions.
These conditions are specified by a set of
conditional statement having the Boolean value true or false.
Each of this condition when met,
transpose the control to execute a block.
A block is a package step of instructions that performs a specific task.
This package can be used in program to perform that specific task.
Whenever the specified condition is met,
one of these blocks is executed.
There are two types of division activities in the new iPod.
They are the If Activity and the Switch Activity.
The If Statement contains a statement with a condition
attached and two sets of instructions as an outcome.
They are Then and Else.
Then block Is used to execute a set of action when the condition is true.
Else block is used to execute a set of action when the condition is false.
If Activity is useful to make a decision based on the value of the variable.
For example, an automation to input a candidate name and
score obtained in an exam and decide if he has passed the exam or not.
Here, the condition is specified in the If Activity ,
which displays the result accordingly.
If the score is greater than or equal to 60,
then we have a message which says,
"Congratulations, you have passed."
If the condition is false,
then you get a message saying,
"Sorry, you have failed."
Switch Activity executes a set of statements out of multiple,
based on the value of a specific expression.
It is used in place of an If Activity,
when at least 3 potential courses of actions are needed.
It can be useful to categorize data according to a custom number of cases.
Here, the condition does not hold a Boolean value like in the case of If Statement,
but it holds multiple values.
By default, the Switch Activity uses the integer argument,
but it can be changed from the properties panel,
from the argument type list.
Switch Activity can be used to store data into
multiple spreadsheets or sort through names of employees.
For example, a week has seven days.
Each of the seven days can be associated with the number 1-7,
that is from Monday to Sunday.
To display the name of the day associated with a particular number,
seven cases are built using
this Switch activity and for any number who are not in the range of 1-7,
the default block will be executed.
If and Switch are both used for decision control.
However, there are few differences between them.
In the If Activity,
the execution of a particular set of action,
that has the Then or else block,
depends upon the value of the condition that is true or false.
It uses multiple statements for multiple choice.
It evaluates in digital character,
pointer, floating type, or the Boolean type.
In Switch Activity, the execution of a particular satisfaction is decided by the user.
It uses single expression for multiple choices.
Evaluates only character or an integer data type.
The use of Switch Activity is preferred over If Activity,
because it is easier to debug and read.