In this section, we will see how to use the types of control flow in the UiPath Studio.
To start with, we will use the if control flow statement.
Here, in this example,
we are trying to find whether the number
entered from the user is an even number or an odd number.
To do so, we have taken a foster activity as the input dialog activity.
Here, the user will enter a number.
The corresponding number will be stored in a variable called as numbers.
As you can see, there is a variable created here,
a number of the type integer.
After the user has entered the number,
the control goes to the if activity.
In the if activity under the condition,
we are implying the conditions for
finding out whether the number is an even or an odd number.
Depending upon the outcome of the condition that is true or false,
the following then, or else block will be executed.
If the number mod 2 is equal to 0,
then this message box is printed,
which says the entered number is an even number.
If this condition evaluates to false,
then the control goes to the else block and then this message box is displayed,
which says the entered number is an odd number.
Let us run this example.
Here there is the input dialog box,
which is asking ''enter the number.''
Let us enter an even number.
As you can see, we got a message box and it says the entered number is an even number.
Let us try to run it one more time,
and this time we will give an odd number. There we go.
You've got the correct message box which says the entered number is an odd number.
Let us look at the switch example.
Here, in the program we are printing the days of the week,
depending upon the number inputted from the user.
To start with, we have used an input dialog activity,
which is asking the user to enter a number.
The entered number is stored in a variable called as number.
The control then flows to the switch activity.
In the switch activity under the expression,
we have passed the numbers.
Depending upon the value that the number is holding we have made seven cases accordingly.
Case one prints it's ''Monday,'' case
two ''Tuesday,'' case three ''Wednesday,'' and the last case seven,
prints it's ''Sunday. ''
If the user enters a number which is not in the range of one to seven,
we have a default block which brings the message,
''enter the number within the range.''
Let us run this example.
Here there's an input box which is asking for the number.
Let us give the number as two.
We're expecting the output should be Tuesday, perfect.
Let us run this example again and will give number eight.
In this case, we should get the message box,
which is displayed in this default Block.
Perfect. For it says ''enter the number within the range one to seven.''