A loop statement in a program will repeat itself
till a given sector for instruction is met or valid.
For example, suppose the user wants to create a program that counts from one to 10.
The user may want to restart the count once it is complete. This is a loop.
The user can continue doing so as long as desired.
At the instance, when the user does not want to count again,
he breaks out of the loop.
Here, count one to 10 is the instruction,
count again is the condition.
As long as the condition is met, the count continues.
Loop represents an important part of automation as they enable the user
to easily check dependencies between variables, activities, and conditions.
Once created, they enable the user to run a segment of the automation
for a specific number of times until a condition is met or indefinitely.
There are three types of loop in UiPath.
The first one is do-while.
It executes the contained activities first and then checks if the condition is true.
This also means that a do-while loop will be executed at least once,
even if the condition is not true.
The second loop is a While loop.
It executes the contained activities while the condition is true.
It checks the condition at the beginning before getting into the loop.
The third type of loop,
as a for-each loop.
It lets the user iterate through element of list,
data-sets and et cetera,
and perform an action on each element individually.
The do-while activity enables the user to create a loop that
executes a specified part of automation while a condition is met.
The sequence is executed at least once,
and the condition is evaluated before each execution of the sequence.
When the specified condition is no longer met,
the program exits the loop.
This type of activity can be useful to step through
all the elements of an array or execute a particular activity multiple time.
The user can increment counter to browse through arrays,
indexes or step through a list of items.
For example, a program to input an even number.
The do-while loop keeps asking for an input until an even number is entered.
The while activity enables the user to create a loop that
executes a specific processes repeatedly while a specific condition is met.
The condition is evaluated before each execution of the sequence.
The main difference between a while and do-while activity is that in
while the condition is evaluated before the body of the loop is executed.
This type of activity can be useful to step through
all the elements of an array or execute a particular activity multiple times.
The user can increment counter to browse through
array indexes or step through a list of items.
For example, a program that checks if the age of the user,
is less than 18.
It performs an activity or a series of activity on each element of a collection.
The for-each activity enables the user to step through arrays, list, data tables,
or other types of collection,
so that the user can iterate through the data
and process each piece of information individually.
This is useful in data processing.
Consider an array of integers.
for-each would enable the robot to check whether
it numeric item fulfills a certain condition.