Now, let us look at a DoWhile example.
In this example, we are printing a set of numbers
starting from one until a point where the user wants to print the number.
To start with, we have used and input dialog activity.
The input dialog activity is asking the last number of the range.
The user enters the number,
and that number is stored in a variable called as last number.
After that, the control flows goes to the do while activity.
In the do-while activity,
we are using a right line activity which prints the number in the output console.
We are using the assign activity to increase the number by one.
Here in the condition we have mentioned,
if the number is less than or equal to the last number,
that means for each and every iteration,
it will check if the current number is less
than or equal to the last number provided by the user.
If the number is still in the range,
it will keep on printing the number.
Once the number is equal to the last number or it becomes greater than the last number,
then the do-while blog will not
execute and the control will come out of the do while activity.
Let us run this example.
Here you can see there is an input dialog box which
is asking entered the last number of the range.
Let me put the number as 10.
So we are assuming we will get the output which starts from 1 ,2,
3, 4 and it prints until 10.
Let's click on Okay.
Let us open the output panel and here you can see we have the numbers starting from 1,
2, 3, 4, 5, 6 until 10.
Let us look at the While example now.
In this example, we are trying to print the even numbers between 1-10.
To do so, we have used a while activity.
In the While activity,
we are specifying the condition.
If the number is less than or equal to 10,
the number variable has been initialized and
the default value is 1 because we need to start from 1.
Inside the while activity we have used an if
activity to check if the number is divisible by 2.
If yes, we will print the number or else we will do nothing.
After that we are incrementing the number by 1 so that we can check if that number,
again is an even number or not.
Let us run this example.
There we go, so we are getting 2,
4, 6, 8, and 10. Perfect.