Let us look at the forEach example now.
In this example, we have created an array of the string type.
You can select the type from here.
You can choose array of T,
and you can give the value of T as string over here.
This array that consists of four names,
and the variable is employee name.
We will use forEach activity.
In this forEach activity,
we are passing the array name here.
Now, each and every element from
the array will be taken and it will be stored inside this item.
Inside the forEach, we are printing the item.
That means for the first iteration out of
the entire array Heba will be picked up and it will be printed.
On the second iteration,
Christa will be picked up and it will be printed.
It will go till the last element that is Heather in our case,
and it will print the last element.
Let us run this example.
As you can see, we got the first name, the second,
third, fourth, and then now the automation should stop.
Perfect.