Now that we have learned how to use the if activity in Uipath,
let us implement it in this exercise.
In this exercise, you have to build a workflow which asks the user,
do you want to get the second marshmallow or not?
For that you have to ask the user,
"Do you want to eat the first marshmallow now or after five minutes?"
If the user answer is now,
we need to respond to him saying, "Oops!
You will not get the second marshmallow."
Else if the answer is after five minutes you have to response saying,
"Congratulations, you will also get your second marshmallow."
If the user enters the option other than now or after five minutes,
you have to respond to him saying, "Invalid option."
Let us see the code for it.
We have begun choosing a sequence.
Inside the sequence, we have used an input dialog activity.
In the input dialog activity we will ask the user,
when does he want to eat the marshmallow?
As in now or after five minutes?
The user answers will be stored into variable coalesce user input.
Depending upon the user input,
we will do a condition check using the if activity.
If the user option is now,
we will directly print a message saying, "Oops!
You will not get the second marshmallow."
Or in the else part,
we will do one more condition check.
Here we will check if the user input is after five minutes.
If this condition is true,
we will print the message.
"Congrats! You will get the second marshmallow."
Or else, if the user has given an input which is neither now or after five minutes,
here we will print a message saying, "Invalid input."
Let us run this workflow.
Let us give the option as now.
Perfect. So we have got the message saying, "Oops!
You will not get this second marshmallow."
Let us give the input as after five minutes.
Let's hit Okay.
You've got the message saying, "Congrats!
You will get the second marshmallow."
Now, let us try to give an input apart from this two options.
Let us give the option user input as never.
Lets hit "Okay" and you got the message saying this is an invalid input.