Now that we have learned how to use a switch activity in UiPath,
let us try to implement it in this exercise.
Here, you have to build a workflow which ask the user about their eye color.
Depending upon the eye color,
you have to give a personality message to the user.
First, you have to ask the user his eye color.
If the user enters blue,
you have to give a message saying,
"You must be very brave."
If the eye color is green,
the message should be,
"You must be generous."
If the eye color is gray,
the message should be,
"You must be very wise."
If the eye color is black,
the message should be,
"You must be very bold."
Let us see the solution for it.
Here, we started using a sequence.
Inside the sequence, we are using
an input dialog box which is asking for the color of the eye.
The user input is stored in a variable called eye color.
Next we are using a switch activity.
In the switch activity under the expression,
we are passing the user input.
If the input from the user is blue,
we will pass the message, "You are brave."
If it is green, we will pass the message, "You are generous."
If it is gray,
we will pass the message,
"You are very wise."
If it is black, you will pass the message,
"You are very bold."
Now, if the user enters any other column,
the control will go to the default block and here we will say,
"Can't recognize that color."
Let us run this example.
First, we will enter black and you got the answer,
"You must be very bold."
Let us execute it and give the input as green.
Here it says, "You must be generous."
Now, let us give a color, brown.
As you can see, the control goes to the default block which prints the message,
"Can't recognize that color."
The reason, we have only made cases for color blue,
green, gray and black.