Now that we have learned about loops in UiPath,
let us try to implement it in this exercise.
Here you have to build a workflow for guessing a number.
First, we need to generate a random number in
the studio and then prompt the user to input a number.
In case of a round input,
we have to display a message saying,
please entered a lesser or a greater number.
The loop should keep on running till
the input number is equal to the generated number in the studio.
Let us look at the solution.
Here we are starting it with a sequence.
Inside the sequence, we are using a do-while loop.
In the do-while loop,
we are first taking an input dialog activity.
In the input dialog activity,
we are asking the user to guess a number.
Before that, in the Variables panel,
we have generated a random variable and we have assigned the value as 25.
Now, depending on the number that the user has given,
we will do a condition check.
If the number entered by the user is equal to the number that we have generated,
then we'll put a message box saying,
you guessed it correct.
As we are going to do a different condition check,
here we will check if the number entered by
the user is greater than the number that we generated.
If so, they will print a message saying,
please enter a smaller number.
Or else they will pass a message to the user,
saying, please enter a grater number.
This loop will keep on running till the time
the number entered from the user and the number generated is not equal.
The moment both the number becomes equal or the condition evaluates to true,
we will break the loop and the program will exterminate.
Let us run this example.
Let us enter a number.
The generated number is 25,
let us enter 20 as the input.
As you can see, we've got a message box saying,
please try a greater number.
Let us give 30 as the input.
Here we got a message saying,
please try a smaller number.
Let us give the number as 25.
Perfect, we got the correct answer.