As discussed earlier, In addition to
decision-based and iteration-based control flow activities,
there are other activities in UiPath that help in controlling the flow of the program.
These are Delay, Break,
Assign, Continue, and Parallel.
The Delay activity enables the user to pause the automation for a custom period time.
The duration can be set from the properties panel under the duration tab in hours,
minutes, and seconds format.
This activity is useful in projects that requires good timing,
such as waiting for a specific application to start or waiting for
some information to be processed so that it can be used in another activity.
For example, here is the sequence displayed by 20 seconds after the text.
This is the start time displayed.
The break activity enables the user to stop the loop at a chosen point,
and then continue with the next activity.
For example, using break activity,
the user exits the For loop activity and
continues the workflow with the activities that follows it.
The Break activity can be used in all the three loops,
that is, While, Do While, and For Each.
Assign activity allocates any value to a variable or argument.
Other control flow activity,
it can be used to increment the value of a variable in a loop,
sum up the value of two or more variables,
and assign the result to a different variable,
or assign a value to an array.
For example, the activity inputs a username and assign it to a variable.
The Continue activity skips the current 'For
Each' iteration and continues to the next iteration.
For example, continue activity used with
a condition using the if activity inside of For Each loop.
The Parallel activity executes child activities in Parallel.
This means that by using Parallel,
multiple activities can be executed side-by-side.
It is helpful when there is need to run several processes at the same time.
Parallel activities lets the user schedule
two or more child activities branches for processing simultaneously.
However, it cannot run multiple processes in foreground at the same time.
In order to run more than one process at the same time,
the user has to choose a single activity branch to run in the foreground,
and the remaining activity branches have to run in the background.
To do this, send window message or the Simulate Type property of the activities are used.
If send window messages or Simulate Type is not used,
then the Parallel activity begins
processing with the execution of one activity branch at a time.
It completes one activity branch and then randomly picks another activity branch.
It gives the result randomly when a user allows this process in the parent activity.
For example, there are five Type Into activities
numbered one to five placed in the Parallel activities.
On the execution, the activities may give results randomly,
such as three, four, five, one,
two or three, two,
five, four, one, and so on.