Now that we have learned how to use the advanced control flow in UiPath,
let us use that concept in this exercise.
Let us first try to understand what is the use case.
In this workflow, you have to calculate the sum
of five positive numbers entered by the user,
but we have two conditions for that.
The condition one is,
if the user enters a negative number,
we need to skip the calculation.
That means we are not going to add the negative numbers entered by the user.
The second condition is,
if the user enters zero as the number,
we need to break the loop, as in,
we need to break the addiction then and there itself and display the sum directly.
Let us see the code for it.
To begin, we have chosen a sequence for it,
and inside the sequence,
we have used an assign activity where we
are initializing a variable called as sum with zero.
This sum is the variable that we will keep on adding our result into it.
We have used a for reach loop to iterate for the five times.
Inside the for reach loop,
we're using an input dialog activity,
and we are asking the user to enter the number for the addition.
The number entered from the user is stored into a variable called num.
Now, we will do a condition check on the number entered by the user.
If the number is less than zero,
that means if the number is a negative number,
we'll directly call the continue activity,
as in, we will not do any addition and we will skip to the next iteration.
But if the number is greater than zero,
then we have a different set of condition check over here.
Here we will first check if the number is zero.
If the number is zero,
we will break the loop.
But if the number is not zero, that is,
if the number is a positive number,
then they will do the addition of that number.
We'll do the addition, that is,
sum plus the number entered by the user.
This loop will iterate for five times depending upon the number entered by the user.
After that, we are using a message box to display the addition to the user.
Let us run this exercise.
Let us enter all the five positive integers for default span.
Enter the first number,
so we'll enter one.
Is asking to enter the second number,
we'll enter two, seven, four and five.
Now we got the addition as 19.
Now, let us try to insert a negative number and zero,
will enter a positive number for the first time.
Now, we will enter minus eight as the number.
Now, since we are entering a negative number,
we are not supposed to do a calculation of it.
If we hit Enter right now,
our value should be only positive two.
We will hit zero as the third number and we'll click "Okay".
Now, if you are entering zero,
that means we should break the loop, as in,
we should stop doing the addition and display whatever
is the sum of the number and there you go.
The addition is two because,
on the first iteration we entered two,
on the second iteration we entered a negative number and we are not doing an addition,
and on the third iteration,
we entered zero, and that is the reason the answers is two.