This section introduces variable and its types in your UiPath.
Variables are containers that are used to store multiple types of data.
Using variables makes it easier to label and store
data which can later be used throughout the automation process.
A variable has an initial value which may change during the program.
The value of a variable can change through external input,
data manipulation, or passing from one activity to another.
A collection variable contains multiple data entries of same type.
It is useful to think of a variable like a box that stores data.
For example, a variable named counter
tracks the number of times the user clicked on a specific item.
The user can configure a variable through its properties.
Variables have the following properties.
The first property is name.
The name of a variable is its unique ID.
It represents the title of the information that has been stored by the variable.
A variable should be named to represent all possible values that it might contain.
The name is essential in programming
because the user access the variable through the name.
Every variable must have a unique name,
and it should be descriptive enough so that other users can easily read it and save time.
The second property is type.
Type defines the kind of data that a variable is intended to store.
The type is declared when the variable is created.
There are some specific types that are more
generic and can accommodate different types of data.
The most common universal types of variables are string,
integer, array, date time,
Boolean, and data tables.
The third property is value.
Value is the data that a variable holds.
The value of a variable changes throughout the process.
Suppose a variable named task is assigned a value 12 initially.
At another point, task may be assigned the value 27.
If no initial value is assigned at the creation of the variable,
a default rule assigns a value to the variable.
The forth and and the last property is scope.
Scope defines from where the variable can be accessed in the workflow.
The variables can be broad or specific.
When the user defines a variable for the first time through the variable panel,
it has a broad scope.
That is, it can be accessed from every part of the program.
If the user defines a variable with a specific scope,
then outside processes cannot access it.
There are always several variables in use,
so the user should avoid making multiple variables
unnecessarily broader as it may cause efficiency issues.