Let's see the best practices for naming a variable.
You use clear and meaningful names.
The name of the variable should accurately describe its content.
Assigned name in a consistent manner.
Adhere to using camel casing.
Keep variable names descriptive and short.
For example, a variable named userName is acceptable versus the variable named uname.
An another example where you can create
a variable name counter versus calling the variable as i,
j, and so on.
The type of variable defines the type of data that can be stored inside the variable.
The different types of variable available in your iPad are: String variables,
Boolean variable, number variable,
date and time variable, data table variable.
This is usually used to store a data which is in the form of rows and columns.
Generic value, QueueItem.
This is a UI path specific variable and Arrays,
these will be discussed in detail in the classroom.
Also, in addition to this,
there are two collection variables,
lists and dictionaries, which also will be discussed later.
Scope field determines the container in which the variable is available.
When the variable is created,
the user chooses the scope from the scope drop-down field,
where all the major sequences and sections of the programs are listed.
The scope of a variable should be defined correctly.
The variables should be defined only in the scope in which they are used.
Making multiple variables unnecessarily available
for entire workflow can cause efficiency issues,
as well as the possibility for confusion.
The user chooses one of these sequences and
the variable will then be available in the part of the walk-throughs.
The scope of the variable is limited to the selected container.
If a variable is declared for a parent activity,
then the variable is available in the entire workflow.
However, if the variable is declared in any specific activity,
then it is available only for the scope of that activity.
The scope of a variable cannot exceed the workflow in which it was defined.