In order to manage the variables in your iPad,
the user needs to perform several actions on them.
These actions can be categorized as,
creating variables, initializing variables, and removing variables.
Let us look at all of them.
To do so, click on the Project panel and open the Main.xaml file,
in the design of panel.
Click on the Activities panel,
and search for an activity named Sequence.
Drag-and-drop the Sequence in the Designer panel.
Let us look at the first way for creating variables.
Click on the Variable panel,
and click on Create a Variable.
Give a name to your variable.
Here, the variable name as first name.
You can choose the variable type as String,
and here we will initialize the variable.
We'll give a default value to our first name variable.
We will use our Message Box activity,
and within the Message Box activity,
we will print the variable.
Let us look at the second way for creating variables.
You can create a variable,
from the Designer panel itself.
To do that, we will use an Assign Activity.
Drag and drop the Assign Activity after the Message Box activity.
In the Assign activity,
you can see we have two properties.
The To and the Value.
Click on the To section and use the shortcut ''Control K'' for creating a new variable.
You can also right-click and say, Create Variable.
Create a variable over here.
We have created a variable with the name employee ID.
Let us change the variable type to Int digital.
Over here, you can provide the value to the variable.
Let us use a Message Box and print the value of the variable.
Let us look at the third way for creating a variable.
You can create a variable from the Properties panel.
To do so, we'll use the Assign Activity again.
Click on the Assign Activity,
and click on the Properties panel.
Here you can see the properties of the Assign Activity.
We have the To property,
and we have the Value property.
We'll click on the To property,
and we'll use the shortcut ''Control K'' for creating a variable.
Hit ''Enter'' for creating a variable.
Here you can see a variable with company name has been created.
We'll change the variable type to String.
We can give the value in the Properties panel itself.
We'll give the company name as Udacity.
We'll use an another Message Box to print the value of the company name variable.
Let us run the process.
Here you can see the first Message Box,
which is the name.
The second Message Box,
which is the employee ID,
and the third Message Box which is the company name.
Let us now look how can we remove variables.
To do so, you can click on the Variable and press the ''Delete'' key from your keyboard.
Also, you can click on the Variable name, and say delete.
Here, we have learned how to create variables.
So variables can be created either using the Variable panel,
the Designer panel, or the Properties panel.
We can delete the variables by hitting the ''Delete'' key,
or by doing the right-click and then selecting ''Delete'.