Now let us understand the concept of scopes in variable.
Over here, we have taken a couple of sequences.
We have the first sequence and we have named it as ScopeEx.
Here we have an another sequence which we have named our sequence ones.
Here be having another sequence which we have named as sequence two.
Let us use an another sequence.
Drag and drop the sequence from the activity panel and place it below the sequence two.
Let us name it to sequence three.
Awesome. Now let us put a message box inside the sequence activity, and we're good to go.
Now in the variables panel,
we have declared for variables ID,
company, name and age.
As you can see here in the scope,
all of them have been assigned the ScopeEx,
that is the parent scope.
Now let us try to change some of these scope of the variable.
Let us click on sequence one and change the scope of the ID to sequence one.
Now, if you go ahead and use the message box of the scope X sequences,
and if you try to print the variable ID over here now you will get an error.
The validation error is saying that the ID is not declared or it is not accessible.
Reason is because we have changed the scope of the ID variable to sequence one.
The movement, we change it back to ScopeEx,
now you can see the error is gone and we have access to the ID variable.
Now the same can be done to all the variables that we have.
So in that case, we will give a variable to each and every sequence.
Now, let's go ahead and change the scope of all the variables that we have over here.
Now, let us go ahead and click on sequence one
and changed the ID company to sequence one.
Let us go ahead and change the sequence two,
and let us put name under the sequence two.
For the sequence three,
let us put age as sequence three.
Awesome. Now, let us try to print some values over here.
As we know that the ID has been assigned the ScopeEx,
as it is we can access it over here.
Now you can easily see the rest three variables are
not available here because they don't belong to this particular scope.
Now, let us look at this sequence one scope.
Now, in the sequence one scope,
as you can see, we have access to two variables.
We have access to a company which is within the scope,
but we also have access to ID variable,
which comes from the parent scope that this ScopeEx.
Now the same goes with sequence two,
and the same also goes with sequence three.
Let us try to print all the variables from here.
Over here, we'll print age in the sequence two,
we will go ahead and print name,
and in the sequence one,
we'll go ahead and print company.
As you can see over here,
the ID is available to all the sequences.
That is it available in within all the scope
because the scope has been saved to the parents scope.
Let us run the workflow and see the output.
Now we got the corresponding output,
that is the ID,
the company, the name, and the age.