Arguments are used to pass data from
one workflow to another by storing the data dynamically.
They are similar to variables as they stored data and pass it on.
However, the variables pass data between activities,
while argument pass data between workflows.
Argument enables user to reuse automation projects,
hence they can be accessed outside the workflow in which they are
defined and are useful in automation projects consisting of multiple workflows.
The user can configure an argument through
its properties which are similar to that of variable accept for one,
that is the argument direction.
The argument have following properties.
The first property is name.
This specifies the name of the argument.
It represents the title of the information that is being stored by the argument.
If the user does not add a name to an argument it is automatically generated.
The second property is direction.
As argument passes data between workflow,
the user needs to specify the direction,
that is from or to which the data is passed.
It can be in,
out, and in out.
The third property is argument type.
It defines the data that the argument is intended to store.
In new iPod, the type is declared when the argument is created.
The types of arguments are string,
numbers, RAs, datetime, Boolean, and data table.
The fourth property is default value.
It is the data that the argument holds.
Argument direction sends the application where
the information stored in them is supposed to go.
That is, it specifies the direction from or to which the data is passed.
The directions are in.
The argument can only be used within the given workflow out.
The arguments can be used to pass data outside of a given workflow.
In/out, the argument can be used both within and outside a given workflow.
Argument needs should be prefix for easy identification of the argument direction,
such as if the direction of the argument is in,
but prefix the argument with an underscore.
Here in the example, we can see the argument name as in_FileName.
If the direction of the argument is out,
prefixes the argument name without underscore.
In this example, you can see the argument name is out_TextResult.
If the direction of the argument is in/out,
prefix the argument name with IO.
In this example, you can see the argument name as io_ReplyNumber.
IO represents input and output.
Arguments and variables are quite similar to each other.
They both are used to store information of a particular data type and basket.
But some of the differences between them are
the argument stores data and passes it between the workflows.
Variable also stores data,
but passes between activities.
An argument can be used across multiple workflows,
but a variable is limited to the workflow in which it is defined.
An argument is created and modified through
argument panels whereas a variable is created and modified through variable panel.
An argument is defined by properties such as name,
direction, type, default values,
whereas available as defined by name,
type, scope, and default values.
If a user does not assign a value to an argument,
it does not have any default values,
whereas if a user does not assign a value to
a variable that is automatically assigned a default value.