Let us try to understand how to work with arguments.
To do so, we will make lemonade.
Yes, you heard it right,
we will learn how to work with arguments while making the lemonade.
To do so, we have created two workflows;
the ingredient workflows and the recipe workflows.
The ingredient workflows is responsible to
collect all the ingredients needed for making the lemonade,
and the recipe workflows takes all the ingredients from
the ingredient workflow and then it states the step to prepare the lemonade.
To do so, we have created two input dialog box in the ingredient workflow.
The first dialogue box is asking the user to
enter the quantity of water needed to make a lemonade.
The value has been stored into an argument out_water.
The second dialogue box,
ask the user for the count of lemons needed to make the lemonade.
The user input is stored in an argument out_lemon.
As you can see, the direction of both the argument is out.
Reason, the arguments value from this workflow will be passed on to the recipe workflow.
In the recipe workflow,
we have created two arguments in_lemon and in_water.
The direction is in because it will get the value
from another workflow and then it will prepare the recipe for lemonade.
We can see the message box,
and the message box says,
extract the juice of the in_lemon,
that is the argument;
we convert it into a string,
mix it with the water,
that is in_water argument,
and add a tablespoon of sugar and mix it,
and your lemonade is ready.
This workflow needs two values,
the in_lemon and the in_score water.
Let us go ahead and open the main.xaml file.
In the main.xaml file,
we will invoke both the workflows.
First, we will invoke the ingredient workflow.
We will drag and drop the ingredient workflow here.
Once the ingredient workflow is completed,
we want the recipe workflow to be invoked.
We will drag and drop the recipe workflow underneath the ingredient workflow.
Click on the import argument.
Here, you can see the ingredient workflow is giving out an argument.
We need to store that argument into a variable in the main file.
Let us go ahead and do that.
Control K for creating a variable,
and we'll name the variable as Lemon.
We'll do the same thing for water,
I'll say Control K for creating the variable,
and I'll name the variable as Water.
You can see here,
in the variables panel,
there are two variables created, lemon and water.
What is going to happen now is,
from the ingredient workflow,
the lemon values will be stored in the lemon variable.
The water values will be stored in the variable water.
Now we need to pass these two variables into the recipe workflow.
To do that, click on the import arguments and over here,
pass the variable name.
For in_water, we will pass water as the input;
and for in_lemon, we will pass lemon as the input.
Let us run this process.
The first input dialog box is asking us to enter the quantity of water needed.
We'll say we need 500 ml of water.
Enter the count of lemons,
we'll say we need two count of lemons,
and now you can see the recipe workflows
is called and the argument have been passed correctly.
The messages extract the juice of two lemons, that we stated,
and mix it with 500 ml of water,
that is what we passed,
and add one tablespoon of sugar and mix it.
Your lemonade is ready.