Now that we have learned about arguments in the Uipath,
let us try to implement it in this exercise.
Here, you have to build a workflow which displays
the sum of two numbers taken as the input from the user.
To do so, you have to create a workflow which accepts two number from the user.
You have to create another workflow which does
the addition of these two numbers and prints the value.
Lastly, you have to invoke both of this workflow in the main.xaml file.
Let us see the solution for it.
Here we have a workflow with the name, accept numbers,
which accepts the number from the user, for the addition.
Here, we are using two input dialog box.
The first input dialog box is asking for
the first number and we're storing it into the argument out_num1.
In the second input dialog box,
we're asking the second number for the addition,
and we're storing it into the argument out_num2.
In the argument panel,
you can see the direction for both the argument is out.
Reason we will be giving out the values,
so that another workflow can take the value and do the addition.
The second workflow is the addition workflow.
Here we are doing the addition of both the numbers.
Here, we have created two arguments in_num1
and in_num2 because the direction is in foreboding argument.
Reason we will take the value from another workflow and then do the addition.
Lastly, in the main.xaml file via invoking both the workflows.
Here, in the input argument section,
we have created two variables,
num1 and num2 in the main.xaml file.
The value from out.num1 will be given out to num1.
The values from out.num2 will be given out and stood inside the num2 variable.
Now we will pass the num1 and the num2 variable for in the addition workflow.
Since the direction is in,
we will pass the num1 and num2.
Here, the value of num1 will be assigned to in_num1 and the value of
num2 will be assigned to in_num2 and the addition will be performed.
Let us run the code.
Here, it is asking us to enter the first number.
We will enter the first number as 25.
A second dialog box,
which is asking us to enter the second number.
Here, we will enter the number as five.
Twenty-five plus five, we're assuming the answer should be 30, perfect.